<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<mes:GenericMetadata xmlns:mes="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v2_1/message" xmlns:gen="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v2_1/metadata/generic" xmlns:com="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v2_1/common">
  <mes:Header>
    <mes:ID>IREF1627658184</mes:ID>
    <mes:Test>True</mes:Test>
    <mes:Prepared>2021-07-30T15:16:24</mes:Prepared>
    <mes:Sender id="open-sdg_sdg-build@1-4-0"/>
    <mes:Structure structureID="MDS1">
      <com:Structure>
        <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.metadatastructure.MetadataStructure=IAEG-SDGs:SDG_MSD(0.3)</URN>
      </com:Structure>
    </mes:Structure>
  </mes:Header>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="2192caeb-0fbb-42da-89dc-675d50c6d116">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_ACS_DTP3</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>NP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3 Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.b Support the research and development of vaccines and medicines for the communicable and non-communicable diseases that primarily affect developing countries, provide access to affordable essential medicines and vaccines, in accordance with the Doha Declaration on the TRIPS Agreement and Public Health, which affirms the right of developing countries to use to the full the provisions in the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights regarding flexibilities to protect public health, and, in particular, provide access to medicines for all</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.b.1 Proportion of the target population covered by all vaccines included in their national programme</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This is under SDG 3</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>15 December 2020</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Household survey section</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>+977 01 4229406</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Thapathali, Kathmandu, Nepal</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>info@cbs.gov.np</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicator shows the percentage of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations at any time before the survey.</p><p>According to WHO, immunisation is a proven tool for controlling and eliminating life-threatening infectious diseases and is estimated to avert between 2 to 3 million death each year. Furthermore, it is one of the most cost-effective health investment, with proven strategies that make it accessible to even the most hard-to-reach and vulnerable populations.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Percentage</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CLASS_SYSTEM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Global MICS guidelines by UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The Global MICS Programme was developed by UNICEF in the 1990s as an international multi-purpose household survey programme to support countries in collecting internationally comparable data on a wide range of indicators on the situation of children and women. It measures key indicators that allow countries to generate data for use in policies and programmes, and to monitor progress towards the national goals and global commitments.</p><p>With the completion of three tier of election, Nepal has been transitioning to the federal system from the Unitary system of Government since 2017. Most notable change is the extensive reclassification of geographical locations from rural to urban at the ward level. New municipalities have been declared and old municipalities either been upgraded to sub-metro city or been extended in area by merging several old wards.</p><p>The new structure of Nepal is divided into seven provinces seven provinces (states). The demarcation of the provinces follows districts, Rukum and Nawalparasi, were split into two separate provinces. The districts are divided into urban and rural locations, which are in turn divided into wards. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The sample for the Nepal MICS 2019 was designed to provide estimates for a large number of indicators on the situation of children and women at the national level, for urban and rural areas and seven provinces. The urban and rural areas within each province were identified as the main sampling strata. Kathmandu valley urban is included as a separate stratum as it’s characteristics differ from the rest. Each stratum was a separate domain. The sample of household was selected in two stages. Within each stratum, at the first sampling stage a specified number of census enumerations areas (EA), was selected systematically with probability proportional to size. A household listing was carried out within the selected enumeration areas, identifying the households with and without children under 5 years. In total, 25 households with and without children under 5 were selected in each sample enumeration area through systematic random sampling method. To ensure strong representativeness of children under 5 in the sample, household with children under 5 were oversampled. Where 13 households with children under 5 and 12 households without were selected from listing in each enumeration area. A total sample of 512 enumeration area and 12800 households was selected for the survey. As the sample is not self-weighting, sample weights are used for reporting survey results. </p><p>The sampling frame of Nepal is based on the 2011 National population and Housing Census (NPHC). The census frame is a complete list of all census wards created for the 2011 NPHC. At the time of last census, the urban household population constituted 20% of the total household population. According to the latest changes in the administrative structure, following the federalization of the government, the urban household population increased to 65%. CBS updated the population frame to reflect the current status. In designing the sample for the Nepal MICS, it was very useful to review the sample design and results of the MICS conducted in 2014, documented in the Final Report of that survey. </p><p>Therefore, a multi-stage, stratified cluster sampling approach was used for the selection of the survey sample. The primary sampling units (PSUs) selected at the first stage were the enumeration areas (EAs) defined for the census enumeration. A listing of households was conducted in each sample enumeration area, and a sample of households was selected at the second stage.  </p><p>The questionnaires were based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili and were pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>National official statistical agency that is responsible for conducting, survey and census.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicator aims to measure access to vaccines, including the newly available or underutilized vaccines, at the national level. For monitoring diseases control and impact of vaccines it is important to measure coverage from each vaccine in national immunization.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The calculation of this indicator requires to have reliable information on total number of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations. The quality of such information is heavily dependent on the questionnaire design, the sample size and design and the accuracy of respondents' answers.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicators is calculated by dividing the total number of children who at the age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations the total number of women aged 15-49 years with a live birth in the same period multiplied by 100.  </p><p>Proportion of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations at any time before survey = Number of children age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations/ Total number of children age 12-23 months ×100</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>For the daily monitoring of field work, team supervisors were responsible. Re-interviewing on one household per cluster was mandatory. Skills and performance of interviewer were observed daily.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ADJUSTMENT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="IMPUTATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REG_AGG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics is the official agency to conducts survey and census. It has trained manpower</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The data is available by province and rural and urban.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows MICS 6 guidelines of UNICEF and can be compared across countries.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS), 2020. Nepal Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2019, Survey Findings Report. Kathmandu, Nepal: Central Bureau of Statistics and UNICEF Nepal.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="55350f92-e44e-491c-886a-6e578975dc85">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_ACS_MCV2</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>NP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3 Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.b Support the research and development of vaccines and medicines for the communicable and non-communicable diseases that primarily affect developing countries, provide access to affordable essential medicines and vaccines, in accordance with the Doha Declaration on the TRIPS Agreement and Public Health, which affirms the right of developing countries to use to the full the provisions in the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights regarding flexibilities to protect public health, and, in particular, provide access to medicines for all</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.b.1 Proportion of the target population covered by all vaccines included in their national programme</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This is under SDG 3</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>15 December 2020</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Household survey section</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>+977 01 4229406</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Thapathali, Kathmandu, Nepal</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>info@cbs.gov.np</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicator shows the percentage of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations at any time before the survey.</p><p>According to WHO, immunisation is a proven tool for controlling and eliminating life-threatening infectious diseases and is estimated to avert between 2 to 3 million death each year. Furthermore, it is one of the most cost-effective health investment, with proven strategies that make it accessible to even the most hard-to-reach and vulnerable populations.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Percentage</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CLASS_SYSTEM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Global MICS guidelines by UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The Global MICS Programme was developed by UNICEF in the 1990s as an international multi-purpose household survey programme to support countries in collecting internationally comparable data on a wide range of indicators on the situation of children and women. It measures key indicators that allow countries to generate data for use in policies and programmes, and to monitor progress towards the national goals and global commitments.</p><p>With the completion of three tier of election, Nepal has been transitioning to the federal system from the Unitary system of Government since 2017. Most notable change is the extensive reclassification of geographical locations from rural to urban at the ward level. New municipalities have been declared and old municipalities either been upgraded to sub-metro city or been extended in area by merging several old wards.</p><p>The new structure of Nepal is divided into seven provinces seven provinces (states). The demarcation of the provinces follows districts, Rukum and Nawalparasi, were split into two separate provinces. The districts are divided into urban and rural locations, which are in turn divided into wards. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The sample for the Nepal MICS 2019 was designed to provide estimates for a large number of indicators on the situation of children and women at the national level, for urban and rural areas and seven provinces. The urban and rural areas within each province were identified as the main sampling strata. Kathmandu valley urban is included as a separate stratum as it’s characteristics differ from the rest. Each stratum was a separate domain. The sample of household was selected in two stages. Within each stratum, at the first sampling stage a specified number of census enumerations areas (EA), was selected systematically with probability proportional to size. A household listing was carried out within the selected enumeration areas, identifying the households with and without children under 5 years. In total, 25 households with and without children under 5 were selected in each sample enumeration area through systematic random sampling method. To ensure strong representativeness of children under 5 in the sample, household with children under 5 were oversampled. Where 13 households with children under 5 and 12 households without were selected from listing in each enumeration area. A total sample of 512 enumeration area and 12800 households was selected for the survey. As the sample is not self-weighting, sample weights are used for reporting survey results. </p><p>The sampling frame of Nepal is based on the 2011 National population and Housing Census (NPHC). The census frame is a complete list of all census wards created for the 2011 NPHC. At the time of last census, the urban household population constituted 20% of the total household population. According to the latest changes in the administrative structure, following the federalization of the government, the urban household population increased to 65%. CBS updated the population frame to reflect the current status. In designing the sample for the Nepal MICS, it was very useful to review the sample design and results of the MICS conducted in 2014, documented in the Final Report of that survey. </p><p>Therefore, a multi-stage, stratified cluster sampling approach was used for the selection of the survey sample. The primary sampling units (PSUs) selected at the first stage were the enumeration areas (EAs) defined for the census enumeration. A listing of households was conducted in each sample enumeration area, and a sample of households was selected at the second stage.  </p><p>The questionnaires were based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili and were pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>National official statistical agency that is responsible for conducting, survey and census.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicator aims to measure access to vaccines, including the newly available or underutilized vaccines, at the national level. For monitoring diseases control and impact of vaccines it is important to measure coverage from each vaccine in national immunization.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The calculation of this indicator requires to have reliable information on total number of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations. The quality of such information is heavily dependent on the questionnaire design, the sample size and design and the accuracy of respondents' answers.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicators is calculated by dividing the total number of children who at the age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations the total number of women aged 15-49 years with a live birth in the same period multiplied by 100.  </p><p>Proportion of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations at any time before survey = Number of children age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations/ Total number of children age 12-23 months ×100</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>For the daily monitoring of field work, team supervisors were responsible. Re-interviewing on one household per cluster was mandatory. Skills and performance of interviewer were observed daily.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ADJUSTMENT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="IMPUTATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REG_AGG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics is the official agency to conducts survey and census. It has trained manpower</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The data is available by province and rural and urban.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows MICS 6 guidelines of UNICEF and can be compared across countries.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS), 2020. Nepal Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2019, Survey Findings Report. Kathmandu, Nepal: Central Bureau of Statistics and UNICEF Nepal.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="094e9a05-5f03-4672-a9da-1e5978dcdbe9">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_ACS_PCV3</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>NP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3 Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.b Support the research and development of vaccines and medicines for the communicable and non-communicable diseases that primarily affect developing countries, provide access to affordable essential medicines and vaccines, in accordance with the Doha Declaration on the TRIPS Agreement and Public Health, which affirms the right of developing countries to use to the full the provisions in the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights regarding flexibilities to protect public health, and, in particular, provide access to medicines for all</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.b.1 Proportion of the target population covered by all vaccines included in their national programme</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This is under SDG 3</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>15 December 2020</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Household survey section</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>+977 01 4229406</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Thapathali, Kathmandu, Nepal</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>info@cbs.gov.np</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicator shows the percentage of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations at any time before the survey.</p><p>According to WHO, immunisation is a proven tool for controlling and eliminating life-threatening infectious diseases and is estimated to avert between 2 to 3 million death each year. Furthermore, it is one of the most cost-effective health investment, with proven strategies that make it accessible to even the most hard-to-reach and vulnerable populations.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Percentage</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CLASS_SYSTEM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Global MICS guidelines by UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The Global MICS Programme was developed by UNICEF in the 1990s as an international multi-purpose household survey programme to support countries in collecting internationally comparable data on a wide range of indicators on the situation of children and women. It measures key indicators that allow countries to generate data for use in policies and programmes, and to monitor progress towards the national goals and global commitments.</p><p>With the completion of three tier of election, Nepal has been transitioning to the federal system from the Unitary system of Government since 2017. Most notable change is the extensive reclassification of geographical locations from rural to urban at the ward level. New municipalities have been declared and old municipalities either been upgraded to sub-metro city or been extended in area by merging several old wards.</p><p>The new structure of Nepal is divided into seven provinces seven provinces (states). The demarcation of the provinces follows districts, Rukum and Nawalparasi, were split into two separate provinces. The districts are divided into urban and rural locations, which are in turn divided into wards. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The sample for the Nepal MICS 2019 was designed to provide estimates for a large number of indicators on the situation of children and women at the national level, for urban and rural areas and seven provinces. The urban and rural areas within each province were identified as the main sampling strata. Kathmandu valley urban is included as a separate stratum as it’s characteristics differ from the rest. Each stratum was a separate domain. The sample of household was selected in two stages. Within each stratum, at the first sampling stage a specified number of census enumerations areas (EA), was selected systematically with probability proportional to size. A household listing was carried out within the selected enumeration areas, identifying the households with and without children under 5 years. In total, 25 households with and without children under 5 were selected in each sample enumeration area through systematic random sampling method. To ensure strong representativeness of children under 5 in the sample, household with children under 5 were oversampled. Where 13 households with children under 5 and 12 households without were selected from listing in each enumeration area. A total sample of 512 enumeration area and 12800 households was selected for the survey. As the sample is not self-weighting, sample weights are used for reporting survey results. </p><p>The sampling frame of Nepal is based on the 2011 National population and Housing Census (NPHC). The census frame is a complete list of all census wards created for the 2011 NPHC. At the time of last census, the urban household population constituted 20% of the total household population. According to the latest changes in the administrative structure, following the federalization of the government, the urban household population increased to 65%. CBS updated the population frame to reflect the current status. In designing the sample for the Nepal MICS, it was very useful to review the sample design and results of the MICS conducted in 2014, documented in the Final Report of that survey. </p><p>Therefore, a multi-stage, stratified cluster sampling approach was used for the selection of the survey sample. The primary sampling units (PSUs) selected at the first stage were the enumeration areas (EAs) defined for the census enumeration. A listing of households was conducted in each sample enumeration area, and a sample of households was selected at the second stage.  </p><p>The questionnaires were based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili and were pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>National official statistical agency that is responsible for conducting, survey and census.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicator aims to measure access to vaccines, including the newly available or underutilized vaccines, at the national level. For monitoring diseases control and impact of vaccines it is important to measure coverage from each vaccine in national immunization.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The calculation of this indicator requires to have reliable information on total number of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations. The quality of such information is heavily dependent on the questionnaire design, the sample size and design and the accuracy of respondents' answers.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicators is calculated by dividing the total number of children who at the age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations the total number of women aged 15-49 years with a live birth in the same period multiplied by 100.  </p><p>Proportion of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations at any time before survey = Number of children age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations/ Total number of children age 12-23 months ×100</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>For the daily monitoring of field work, team supervisors were responsible. Re-interviewing on one household per cluster was mandatory. Skills and performance of interviewer were observed daily.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ADJUSTMENT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="IMPUTATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REG_AGG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics is the official agency to conducts survey and census. It has trained manpower</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The data is available by province and rural and urban.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows MICS 6 guidelines of UNICEF and can be compared across countries.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS), 2020. Nepal Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2019, Survey Findings Report. Kathmandu, Nepal: Central Bureau of Statistics and UNICEF Nepal.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="b1ebac6b-8fc1-4abf-a84b-9451487ae37d">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_ACS_VACN</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>NP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3 Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.b Support the research and development of vaccines and medicines for the communicable and non-communicable diseases that primarily affect developing countries, provide access to affordable essential medicines and vaccines, in accordance with the Doha Declaration on the TRIPS Agreement and Public Health, which affirms the right of developing countries to use to the full the provisions in the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights regarding flexibilities to protect public health, and, in particular, provide access to medicines for all</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.b.1 Proportion of the target population covered by all vaccines included in their national programme</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This is under SDG 3</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>15 December 2020</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Household survey section</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>+977 01 4229406</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Thapathali, Kathmandu, Nepal</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>info@cbs.gov.np</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicator shows the percentage of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations at any time before the survey.</p><p>According to WHO, immunisation is a proven tool for controlling and eliminating life-threatening infectious diseases and is estimated to avert between 2 to 3 million death each year. Furthermore, it is one of the most cost-effective health investment, with proven strategies that make it accessible to even the most hard-to-reach and vulnerable populations.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Percentage</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CLASS_SYSTEM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Global MICS guidelines by UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The Global MICS Programme was developed by UNICEF in the 1990s as an international multi-purpose household survey programme to support countries in collecting internationally comparable data on a wide range of indicators on the situation of children and women. It measures key indicators that allow countries to generate data for use in policies and programmes, and to monitor progress towards the national goals and global commitments.</p><p>With the completion of three tier of election, Nepal has been transitioning to the federal system from the Unitary system of Government since 2017. Most notable change is the extensive reclassification of geographical locations from rural to urban at the ward level. New municipalities have been declared and old municipalities either been upgraded to sub-metro city or been extended in area by merging several old wards.</p><p>The new structure of Nepal is divided into seven provinces seven provinces (states). The demarcation of the provinces follows districts, Rukum and Nawalparasi, were split into two separate provinces. The districts are divided into urban and rural locations, which are in turn divided into wards. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The sample for the Nepal MICS 2019 was designed to provide estimates for a large number of indicators on the situation of children and women at the national level, for urban and rural areas and seven provinces. The urban and rural areas within each province were identified as the main sampling strata. Kathmandu valley urban is included as a separate stratum as it’s characteristics differ from the rest. Each stratum was a separate domain. The sample of household was selected in two stages. Within each stratum, at the first sampling stage a specified number of census enumerations areas (EA), was selected systematically with probability proportional to size. A household listing was carried out within the selected enumeration areas, identifying the households with and without children under 5 years. In total, 25 households with and without children under 5 were selected in each sample enumeration area through systematic random sampling method. To ensure strong representativeness of children under 5 in the sample, household with children under 5 were oversampled. Where 13 households with children under 5 and 12 households without were selected from listing in each enumeration area. A total sample of 512 enumeration area and 12800 households was selected for the survey. As the sample is not self-weighting, sample weights are used for reporting survey results. </p><p>The sampling frame of Nepal is based on the 2011 National population and Housing Census (NPHC). The census frame is a complete list of all census wards created for the 2011 NPHC. At the time of last census, the urban household population constituted 20% of the total household population. According to the latest changes in the administrative structure, following the federalization of the government, the urban household population increased to 65%. CBS updated the population frame to reflect the current status. In designing the sample for the Nepal MICS, it was very useful to review the sample design and results of the MICS conducted in 2014, documented in the Final Report of that survey. </p><p>Therefore, a multi-stage, stratified cluster sampling approach was used for the selection of the survey sample. The primary sampling units (PSUs) selected at the first stage were the enumeration areas (EAs) defined for the census enumeration. A listing of households was conducted in each sample enumeration area, and a sample of households was selected at the second stage.  </p><p>The questionnaires were based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili and were pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>National official statistical agency that is responsible for conducting, survey and census.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicator aims to measure access to vaccines, including the newly available or underutilized vaccines, at the national level. For monitoring diseases control and impact of vaccines it is important to measure coverage from each vaccine in national immunization.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The calculation of this indicator requires to have reliable information on total number of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations. The quality of such information is heavily dependent on the questionnaire design, the sample size and design and the accuracy of respondents' answers.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicators is calculated by dividing the total number of children who at the age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations the total number of women aged 15-49 years with a live birth in the same period multiplied by 100.  </p><p>Proportion of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations at any time before survey = Number of children age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations/ Total number of children age 12-23 months ×100</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>For the daily monitoring of field work, team supervisors were responsible. Re-interviewing on one household per cluster was mandatory. Skills and performance of interviewer were observed daily.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ADJUSTMENT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="IMPUTATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REG_AGG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics is the official agency to conducts survey and census. It has trained manpower</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The data is available by province and rural and urban.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows MICS 6 guidelines of UNICEF and can be compared across countries.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS), 2020. Nepal Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2019, Survey Findings Report. Kathmandu, Nepal: Central Bureau of Statistics and UNICEF Nepal.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="865153da-2a93-41bb-991c-aad341d8d7dd">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_ACS_HPV</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>NP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3 Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.b Support the research and development of vaccines and medicines for the communicable and non-communicable diseases that primarily affect developing countries, provide access to affordable essential medicines and vaccines, in accordance with the Doha Declaration on the TRIPS Agreement and Public Health, which affirms the right of developing countries to use to the full the provisions in the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights regarding flexibilities to protect public health, and, in particular, provide access to medicines for all</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.b.1 Proportion of the target population covered by all vaccines included in their national programme</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This is under SDG 3</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>15 December 2020</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Household survey section</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>+977 01 4229406</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Thapathali, Kathmandu, Nepal</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>info@cbs.gov.np</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicator shows the percentage of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations at any time before the survey.</p><p>According to WHO, immunisation is a proven tool for controlling and eliminating life-threatening infectious diseases and is estimated to avert between 2 to 3 million death each year. Furthermore, it is one of the most cost-effective health investment, with proven strategies that make it accessible to even the most hard-to-reach and vulnerable populations.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Percentage</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CLASS_SYSTEM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Global MICS guidelines by UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The Global MICS Programme was developed by UNICEF in the 1990s as an international multi-purpose household survey programme to support countries in collecting internationally comparable data on a wide range of indicators on the situation of children and women. It measures key indicators that allow countries to generate data for use in policies and programmes, and to monitor progress towards the national goals and global commitments.</p><p>With the completion of three tier of election, Nepal has been transitioning to the federal system from the Unitary system of Government since 2017. Most notable change is the extensive reclassification of geographical locations from rural to urban at the ward level. New municipalities have been declared and old municipalities either been upgraded to sub-metro city or been extended in area by merging several old wards.</p><p>The new structure of Nepal is divided into seven provinces seven provinces (states). The demarcation of the provinces follows districts, Rukum and Nawalparasi, were split into two separate provinces. The districts are divided into urban and rural locations, which are in turn divided into wards. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The sample for the Nepal MICS 2019 was designed to provide estimates for a large number of indicators on the situation of children and women at the national level, for urban and rural areas and seven provinces. The urban and rural areas within each province were identified as the main sampling strata. Kathmandu valley urban is included as a separate stratum as it’s characteristics differ from the rest. Each stratum was a separate domain. The sample of household was selected in two stages. Within each stratum, at the first sampling stage a specified number of census enumerations areas (EA), was selected systematically with probability proportional to size. A household listing was carried out within the selected enumeration areas, identifying the households with and without children under 5 years. In total, 25 households with and without children under 5 were selected in each sample enumeration area through systematic random sampling method. To ensure strong representativeness of children under 5 in the sample, household with children under 5 were oversampled. Where 13 households with children under 5 and 12 households without were selected from listing in each enumeration area. A total sample of 512 enumeration area and 12800 households was selected for the survey. As the sample is not self-weighting, sample weights are used for reporting survey results. </p><p>The sampling frame of Nepal is based on the 2011 National population and Housing Census (NPHC). The census frame is a complete list of all census wards created for the 2011 NPHC. At the time of last census, the urban household population constituted 20% of the total household population. According to the latest changes in the administrative structure, following the federalization of the government, the urban household population increased to 65%. CBS updated the population frame to reflect the current status. In designing the sample for the Nepal MICS, it was very useful to review the sample design and results of the MICS conducted in 2014, documented in the Final Report of that survey. </p><p>Therefore, a multi-stage, stratified cluster sampling approach was used for the selection of the survey sample. The primary sampling units (PSUs) selected at the first stage were the enumeration areas (EAs) defined for the census enumeration. A listing of households was conducted in each sample enumeration area, and a sample of households was selected at the second stage.  </p><p>The questionnaires were based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili and were pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>National official statistical agency that is responsible for conducting, survey and census.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicator aims to measure access to vaccines, including the newly available or underutilized vaccines, at the national level. For monitoring diseases control and impact of vaccines it is important to measure coverage from each vaccine in national immunization.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The calculation of this indicator requires to have reliable information on total number of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations. The quality of such information is heavily dependent on the questionnaire design, the sample size and design and the accuracy of respondents' answers.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicators is calculated by dividing the total number of children who at the age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations the total number of women aged 15-49 years with a live birth in the same period multiplied by 100.  </p><p>Proportion of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations at any time before survey = Number of children age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations/ Total number of children age 12-23 months ×100</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>For the daily monitoring of field work, team supervisors were responsible. Re-interviewing on one household per cluster was mandatory. Skills and performance of interviewer were observed daily.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ADJUSTMENT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="IMPUTATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REG_AGG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics is the official agency to conducts survey and census. It has trained manpower</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The data is available by province and rural and urban.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows MICS 6 guidelines of UNICEF and can be compared across countries.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS), 2020. Nepal Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2019, Survey Findings Report. Kathmandu, Nepal: Central Bureau of Statistics and UNICEF Nepal.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
</mes:GenericMetadata>
        