<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<mes:GenericMetadata xmlns:mes="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v2_1/message" xmlns:gen="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v2_1/metadata/generic" xmlns:com="http://www.sdmx.org/resources/sdmxml/schemas/v2_1/common">
  <mes:Header>
    <mes:ID>IREF1627660311</mes:ID>
    <mes:Test>True</mes:Test>
    <mes:Prepared>2021-07-30T15:51:51</mes:Prepared>
    <mes:Sender id="open-sdg_sdg-build@1-4-0"/>
    <mes:Structure structureID="MDS1">
      <com:Structure>
        <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.metadatastructure.MetadataStructure=IAEG-SDGs:SDG_MSD(0.3)</URN>
      </com:Structure>
    </mes:Structure>
  </mes:Header>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="4d9978d2-3a8c-4abf-af97-58df1995046a">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_STA_BRTC</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>NP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3 Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.1  By 2030, reduce the global maternal mortality ratio to less than 70 per 100,000 live births</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.1.2 Proportion of births attended by skilled health personnel</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This is under SDG 3</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>15 December 2020</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Gender and Social Statistics Section</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>+977 01 4229406</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Thapathali, Kathmandu, Nepal</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>info@cbs.gov.np</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Births that are attended by skilled personnel helps to reduce the health risks to both the mother and child. According to WHO, the risk of complications and infection that can cause morbidity and mortality to mother or baby can be reduced with proper medical attention during delivery.</p><p>Proportion of births attended by skilled personnel (generally doctors, nurses or midwives but can refer to other health professional providing childbirth care) is the proportion of child births attended by professional health personnel. Skilled attendants are medical doctor, nurse and auxiliary nurse midwife (ANM) in Nepal. </p><p>According to current definition provided by WHO, these are competent maternal and new born health (MNH) professionals educated, trained and regulated national and international standards. They are competent to: </p><ol><li>Provide and promote evidence-based, human rights based, quality, socio-culturally sensitive and dignified care to women and new born </li><li>Facilitate physiological process during labour and delivery to ensure a clean and positive childbirth experience </li><li>Identify and manage or refer women and / or new-borns with complications</li></ol>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Percentage</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CLASS_SYSTEM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Global MICS guidelines by UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p> An international multi-purpose household survey programme was developed by UNICEF in the 1990s to support countries in collecting internationally comparable data on a wide range of indicators on the situation of children and women, widely known as global MICS programme. It measures key indicators that allows countries to generate data for using in policy making and designing programs, and to monitor progress towards the national goals and global commitments.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The sample for the Nepal MICS 2019 was designed to provide estimates for a large number of indicators on the situation of children and women at the national level, for urban and rural areas and seven provinces. The urban and rural areas within each province were identified as the main sampling strata. Kathmandu valley urban is included as a separate stratum as it’s characteristics differ from the rest. Each stratum was a separate domain. The sample of household was selected in two stages. Within each stratum, at the first sampling stage a specified number of census enumerations areas (EA), was selected systematically with probability proportional to size. A household listing was carried out within the selected enumeration areas, identifying the households with and without children under 5 years. In total, 25 households with and without children under 5 were selected in each sample enumeration area through systematic random sampling method. To ensure strong representativeness of children under 5 in the sample, household with children under 5 were oversampled. Where 13 households with children under 5 and 12 households without were selected from listing in each enumeration area. A total sample of 512 enumeration area and 12800 households was selected for the survey. As the sample is not self-weighting, sample weights are used for reporting survey results. </p><p>The sampling frame of Nepal is based on the 2011 National population and Housing Census (NPHC). The census frame is a complete list of all census wards created for the 2011 NPHC. At the time of last census, the urban household population constituted 20% of the total household population. According to the latest changes in the administrative structure, following the federalization of the government, the urban household population increased to 65%. CBS updated the population frame to reflect the current status. In designing the sample for the Nepal MICS, it was very useful to review the sample design and results of the MICS conducted in 2014, documented in the Final Report of that survey. </p><p>Therefore, a multi-stage, stratified cluster sampling approach was used for the selection of the survey sample. The primary sampling units (PSUs) selected at the first stage were the enumeration areas (EAs) defined for the census enumeration. A listing of households was conducted in each sample enumeration area, and a sample of households was selected at the second stage.  </p><p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p> 2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>National official statistical agency that is responsible for conducting, survey and census.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Having a skilled health care provider at the time of child birth is an important lifesaving intervention for both women and new-borns. Not having access to this key assistance is detrimental to women&#39;s and new-borns health because it could cause the death of the women and/or the new born or long lasting morbidity Achieving universal coverage for this indicator is therefore essential for reducing maternal and new born mortality.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Births attended by skilled health personnel is an indicator of health care utilization. It is a measure of the health system’s functioning and potential to provide adequate coverage for childbirth. On its own, however, this indicator does not provide insight into the availability or accessibility of services, for example in cases where emergency care if needed. Neither does this indicator capture the quality of care received</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicators is calculated by dividing the total number of women aged 15-49 years with a live births in the last 2 years whose most recent live births was attended by skilled personnel by the total number of live births in the same period multiplied by 100.  </p><p>Proportion of births attended by skilled health personnel = Number of women age 15-49 years with a live birth in the last 2 years whose most recent live birth was attended by skilled health personnel /Total number live births×100</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ADJUSTMENT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="IMPUTATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REG_AGG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics is the official agency to conducts survey and census. It has trained manpower</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The data is available by province and rural and urban.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows MICS 6 guidelines of UNICEF and can be compared across countries.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS), 2020. Nepal Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2019, Survey Findings Report. Kathmandu, Nepal: Central Bureau of Statistics and UNICEF Nepal.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="edb0927b-963c-487c-908b-057d4d6bb5f8">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_ACS_DTP3</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>NP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3 Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.b Support the research and development of vaccines and medicines for the communicable and non-communicable diseases that primarily affect developing countries, provide access to affordable essential medicines and vaccines, in accordance with the Doha Declaration on the TRIPS Agreement and Public Health, which affirms the right of developing countries to use to the full the provisions in the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights regarding flexibilities to protect public health, and, in particular, provide access to medicines for all</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.b.1 Proportion of the target population covered by all vaccines included in their national programme</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This is under SDG 3</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>15 December 2020</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Household survey section</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>+977 01 4229406</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Thapathali, Kathmandu, Nepal</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>info@cbs.gov.np</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicator shows the percentage of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations at any time before the survey.</p><p>According to WHO, immunisation is a proven tool for controlling and eliminating life-threatening infectious diseases and is estimated to avert between 2 to 3 million death each year. Furthermore, it is one of the most cost-effective health investment, with proven strategies that make it accessible to even the most hard-to-reach and vulnerable populations.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Percentage</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CLASS_SYSTEM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Global MICS guidelines by UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The Global MICS Programme was developed by UNICEF in the 1990s as an international multi-purpose household survey programme to support countries in collecting internationally comparable data on a wide range of indicators on the situation of children and women. It measures key indicators that allow countries to generate data for use in policies and programmes, and to monitor progress towards the national goals and global commitments.</p><p>With the completion of three tier of election, Nepal has been transitioning to the federal system from the Unitary system of Government since 2017. Most notable change is the extensive reclassification of geographical locations from rural to urban at the ward level. New municipalities have been declared and old municipalities either been upgraded to sub-metro city or been extended in area by merging several old wards.</p><p>The new structure of Nepal is divided into seven provinces seven provinces (states). The demarcation of the provinces follows districts, Rukum and Nawalparasi, were split into two separate provinces. The districts are divided into urban and rural locations, which are in turn divided into wards. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The sample for the Nepal MICS 2019 was designed to provide estimates for a large number of indicators on the situation of children and women at the national level, for urban and rural areas and seven provinces. The urban and rural areas within each province were identified as the main sampling strata. Kathmandu valley urban is included as a separate stratum as it’s characteristics differ from the rest. Each stratum was a separate domain. The sample of household was selected in two stages. Within each stratum, at the first sampling stage a specified number of census enumerations areas (EA), was selected systematically with probability proportional to size. A household listing was carried out within the selected enumeration areas, identifying the households with and without children under 5 years. In total, 25 households with and without children under 5 were selected in each sample enumeration area through systematic random sampling method. To ensure strong representativeness of children under 5 in the sample, household with children under 5 were oversampled. Where 13 households with children under 5 and 12 households without were selected from listing in each enumeration area. A total sample of 512 enumeration area and 12800 households was selected for the survey. As the sample is not self-weighting, sample weights are used for reporting survey results. </p><p>The sampling frame of Nepal is based on the 2011 National population and Housing Census (NPHC). The census frame is a complete list of all census wards created for the 2011 NPHC. At the time of last census, the urban household population constituted 20% of the total household population. According to the latest changes in the administrative structure, following the federalization of the government, the urban household population increased to 65%. CBS updated the population frame to reflect the current status. In designing the sample for the Nepal MICS, it was very useful to review the sample design and results of the MICS conducted in 2014, documented in the Final Report of that survey. </p><p>Therefore, a multi-stage, stratified cluster sampling approach was used for the selection of the survey sample. The primary sampling units (PSUs) selected at the first stage were the enumeration areas (EAs) defined for the census enumeration. A listing of households was conducted in each sample enumeration area, and a sample of households was selected at the second stage.  </p><p>The questionnaires were based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili and were pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>National official statistical agency that is responsible for conducting, survey and census.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicator aims to measure access to vaccines, including the newly available or underutilized vaccines, at the national level. For monitoring diseases control and impact of vaccines it is important to measure coverage from each vaccine in national immunization.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The calculation of this indicator requires to have reliable information on total number of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations. The quality of such information is heavily dependent on the questionnaire design, the sample size and design and the accuracy of respondents&#39; answers.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicators is calculated by dividing the total number of children who at the age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations the total number of women aged 15-49 years with a live birth in the same period multiplied by 100.  </p><p>Proportion of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations at any time before survey = Number of children age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations/ Total number of children age 12-23 months ×100</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>For the daily monitoring of field work, team supervisors were responsible. Re-interviewing on one household per cluster was mandatory. Skills and performance of interviewer were observed daily.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ADJUSTMENT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="IMPUTATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REG_AGG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics is the official agency to conducts survey and census. It has trained manpower</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The data is available by province and rural and urban.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows MICS 6 guidelines of UNICEF and can be compared across countries.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS), 2020. Nepal Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2019, Survey Findings Report. Kathmandu, Nepal: Central Bureau of Statistics and UNICEF Nepal.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="b907a3ae-3e40-4fec-8e5c-c1dccf9d9310">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_ACS_MCV2</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>NP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3 Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.b Support the research and development of vaccines and medicines for the communicable and non-communicable diseases that primarily affect developing countries, provide access to affordable essential medicines and vaccines, in accordance with the Doha Declaration on the TRIPS Agreement and Public Health, which affirms the right of developing countries to use to the full the provisions in the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights regarding flexibilities to protect public health, and, in particular, provide access to medicines for all</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.b.1 Proportion of the target population covered by all vaccines included in their national programme</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This is under SDG 3</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>15 December 2020</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Household survey section</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>+977 01 4229406</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Thapathali, Kathmandu, Nepal</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>info@cbs.gov.np</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicator shows the percentage of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations at any time before the survey.</p><p>According to WHO, immunisation is a proven tool for controlling and eliminating life-threatening infectious diseases and is estimated to avert between 2 to 3 million death each year. Furthermore, it is one of the most cost-effective health investment, with proven strategies that make it accessible to even the most hard-to-reach and vulnerable populations.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Percentage</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CLASS_SYSTEM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Global MICS guidelines by UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The Global MICS Programme was developed by UNICEF in the 1990s as an international multi-purpose household survey programme to support countries in collecting internationally comparable data on a wide range of indicators on the situation of children and women. It measures key indicators that allow countries to generate data for use in policies and programmes, and to monitor progress towards the national goals and global commitments.</p><p>With the completion of three tier of election, Nepal has been transitioning to the federal system from the Unitary system of Government since 2017. Most notable change is the extensive reclassification of geographical locations from rural to urban at the ward level. New municipalities have been declared and old municipalities either been upgraded to sub-metro city or been extended in area by merging several old wards.</p><p>The new structure of Nepal is divided into seven provinces seven provinces (states). The demarcation of the provinces follows districts, Rukum and Nawalparasi, were split into two separate provinces. The districts are divided into urban and rural locations, which are in turn divided into wards. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The sample for the Nepal MICS 2019 was designed to provide estimates for a large number of indicators on the situation of children and women at the national level, for urban and rural areas and seven provinces. The urban and rural areas within each province were identified as the main sampling strata. Kathmandu valley urban is included as a separate stratum as it’s characteristics differ from the rest. Each stratum was a separate domain. The sample of household was selected in two stages. Within each stratum, at the first sampling stage a specified number of census enumerations areas (EA), was selected systematically with probability proportional to size. A household listing was carried out within the selected enumeration areas, identifying the households with and without children under 5 years. In total, 25 households with and without children under 5 were selected in each sample enumeration area through systematic random sampling method. To ensure strong representativeness of children under 5 in the sample, household with children under 5 were oversampled. Where 13 households with children under 5 and 12 households without were selected from listing in each enumeration area. A total sample of 512 enumeration area and 12800 households was selected for the survey. As the sample is not self-weighting, sample weights are used for reporting survey results. </p><p>The sampling frame of Nepal is based on the 2011 National population and Housing Census (NPHC). The census frame is a complete list of all census wards created for the 2011 NPHC. At the time of last census, the urban household population constituted 20% of the total household population. According to the latest changes in the administrative structure, following the federalization of the government, the urban household population increased to 65%. CBS updated the population frame to reflect the current status. In designing the sample for the Nepal MICS, it was very useful to review the sample design and results of the MICS conducted in 2014, documented in the Final Report of that survey. </p><p>Therefore, a multi-stage, stratified cluster sampling approach was used for the selection of the survey sample. The primary sampling units (PSUs) selected at the first stage were the enumeration areas (EAs) defined for the census enumeration. A listing of households was conducted in each sample enumeration area, and a sample of households was selected at the second stage.  </p><p>The questionnaires were based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili and were pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>National official statistical agency that is responsible for conducting, survey and census.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicator aims to measure access to vaccines, including the newly available or underutilized vaccines, at the national level. For monitoring diseases control and impact of vaccines it is important to measure coverage from each vaccine in national immunization.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The calculation of this indicator requires to have reliable information on total number of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations. The quality of such information is heavily dependent on the questionnaire design, the sample size and design and the accuracy of respondents&#39; answers.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicators is calculated by dividing the total number of children who at the age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations the total number of women aged 15-49 years with a live birth in the same period multiplied by 100.  </p><p>Proportion of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations at any time before survey = Number of children age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations/ Total number of children age 12-23 months ×100</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>For the daily monitoring of field work, team supervisors were responsible. Re-interviewing on one household per cluster was mandatory. Skills and performance of interviewer were observed daily.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ADJUSTMENT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="IMPUTATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REG_AGG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics is the official agency to conducts survey and census. It has trained manpower</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The data is available by province and rural and urban.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows MICS 6 guidelines of UNICEF and can be compared across countries.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS), 2020. Nepal Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2019, Survey Findings Report. Kathmandu, Nepal: Central Bureau of Statistics and UNICEF Nepal.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="c2aa1ac9-77e1-4788-9edf-5e7409384a4b">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_ACS_PCV3</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>NP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3 Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.b Support the research and development of vaccines and medicines for the communicable and non-communicable diseases that primarily affect developing countries, provide access to affordable essential medicines and vaccines, in accordance with the Doha Declaration on the TRIPS Agreement and Public Health, which affirms the right of developing countries to use to the full the provisions in the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights regarding flexibilities to protect public health, and, in particular, provide access to medicines for all</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.b.1 Proportion of the target population covered by all vaccines included in their national programme</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This is under SDG 3</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>15 December 2020</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Household survey section</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>+977 01 4229406</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Thapathali, Kathmandu, Nepal</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>info@cbs.gov.np</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicator shows the percentage of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations at any time before the survey.</p><p>According to WHO, immunisation is a proven tool for controlling and eliminating life-threatening infectious diseases and is estimated to avert between 2 to 3 million death each year. Furthermore, it is one of the most cost-effective health investment, with proven strategies that make it accessible to even the most hard-to-reach and vulnerable populations.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Percentage</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CLASS_SYSTEM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Global MICS guidelines by UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The Global MICS Programme was developed by UNICEF in the 1990s as an international multi-purpose household survey programme to support countries in collecting internationally comparable data on a wide range of indicators on the situation of children and women. It measures key indicators that allow countries to generate data for use in policies and programmes, and to monitor progress towards the national goals and global commitments.</p><p>With the completion of three tier of election, Nepal has been transitioning to the federal system from the Unitary system of Government since 2017. Most notable change is the extensive reclassification of geographical locations from rural to urban at the ward level. New municipalities have been declared and old municipalities either been upgraded to sub-metro city or been extended in area by merging several old wards.</p><p>The new structure of Nepal is divided into seven provinces seven provinces (states). The demarcation of the provinces follows districts, Rukum and Nawalparasi, were split into two separate provinces. The districts are divided into urban and rural locations, which are in turn divided into wards. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The sample for the Nepal MICS 2019 was designed to provide estimates for a large number of indicators on the situation of children and women at the national level, for urban and rural areas and seven provinces. The urban and rural areas within each province were identified as the main sampling strata. Kathmandu valley urban is included as a separate stratum as it’s characteristics differ from the rest. Each stratum was a separate domain. The sample of household was selected in two stages. Within each stratum, at the first sampling stage a specified number of census enumerations areas (EA), was selected systematically with probability proportional to size. A household listing was carried out within the selected enumeration areas, identifying the households with and without children under 5 years. In total, 25 households with and without children under 5 were selected in each sample enumeration area through systematic random sampling method. To ensure strong representativeness of children under 5 in the sample, household with children under 5 were oversampled. Where 13 households with children under 5 and 12 households without were selected from listing in each enumeration area. A total sample of 512 enumeration area and 12800 households was selected for the survey. As the sample is not self-weighting, sample weights are used for reporting survey results. </p><p>The sampling frame of Nepal is based on the 2011 National population and Housing Census (NPHC). The census frame is a complete list of all census wards created for the 2011 NPHC. At the time of last census, the urban household population constituted 20% of the total household population. According to the latest changes in the administrative structure, following the federalization of the government, the urban household population increased to 65%. CBS updated the population frame to reflect the current status. In designing the sample for the Nepal MICS, it was very useful to review the sample design and results of the MICS conducted in 2014, documented in the Final Report of that survey. </p><p>Therefore, a multi-stage, stratified cluster sampling approach was used for the selection of the survey sample. The primary sampling units (PSUs) selected at the first stage were the enumeration areas (EAs) defined for the census enumeration. A listing of households was conducted in each sample enumeration area, and a sample of households was selected at the second stage.  </p><p>The questionnaires were based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili and were pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>National official statistical agency that is responsible for conducting, survey and census.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicator aims to measure access to vaccines, including the newly available or underutilized vaccines, at the national level. For monitoring diseases control and impact of vaccines it is important to measure coverage from each vaccine in national immunization.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The calculation of this indicator requires to have reliable information on total number of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations. The quality of such information is heavily dependent on the questionnaire design, the sample size and design and the accuracy of respondents&#39; answers.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicators is calculated by dividing the total number of children who at the age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations the total number of women aged 15-49 years with a live birth in the same period multiplied by 100.  </p><p>Proportion of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations at any time before survey = Number of children age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations/ Total number of children age 12-23 months ×100</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>For the daily monitoring of field work, team supervisors were responsible. Re-interviewing on one household per cluster was mandatory. Skills and performance of interviewer were observed daily.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ADJUSTMENT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="IMPUTATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REG_AGG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics is the official agency to conducts survey and census. It has trained manpower</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The data is available by province and rural and urban.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows MICS 6 guidelines of UNICEF and can be compared across countries.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS), 2020. Nepal Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2019, Survey Findings Report. Kathmandu, Nepal: Central Bureau of Statistics and UNICEF Nepal.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="b51fb56e-5402-4ed0-9f32-9ccb7f3cd891">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_ACS_VACN</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>NP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3 Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.b Support the research and development of vaccines and medicines for the communicable and non-communicable diseases that primarily affect developing countries, provide access to affordable essential medicines and vaccines, in accordance with the Doha Declaration on the TRIPS Agreement and Public Health, which affirms the right of developing countries to use to the full the provisions in the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights regarding flexibilities to protect public health, and, in particular, provide access to medicines for all</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.b.1 Proportion of the target population covered by all vaccines included in their national programme</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This is under SDG 3</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>15 December 2020</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Household survey section</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>+977 01 4229406</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Thapathali, Kathmandu, Nepal</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>info@cbs.gov.np</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicator shows the percentage of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations at any time before the survey.</p><p>According to WHO, immunisation is a proven tool for controlling and eliminating life-threatening infectious diseases and is estimated to avert between 2 to 3 million death each year. Furthermore, it is one of the most cost-effective health investment, with proven strategies that make it accessible to even the most hard-to-reach and vulnerable populations.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Percentage</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CLASS_SYSTEM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Global MICS guidelines by UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The Global MICS Programme was developed by UNICEF in the 1990s as an international multi-purpose household survey programme to support countries in collecting internationally comparable data on a wide range of indicators on the situation of children and women. It measures key indicators that allow countries to generate data for use in policies and programmes, and to monitor progress towards the national goals and global commitments.</p><p>With the completion of three tier of election, Nepal has been transitioning to the federal system from the Unitary system of Government since 2017. Most notable change is the extensive reclassification of geographical locations from rural to urban at the ward level. New municipalities have been declared and old municipalities either been upgraded to sub-metro city or been extended in area by merging several old wards.</p><p>The new structure of Nepal is divided into seven provinces seven provinces (states). The demarcation of the provinces follows districts, Rukum and Nawalparasi, were split into two separate provinces. The districts are divided into urban and rural locations, which are in turn divided into wards. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The sample for the Nepal MICS 2019 was designed to provide estimates for a large number of indicators on the situation of children and women at the national level, for urban and rural areas and seven provinces. The urban and rural areas within each province were identified as the main sampling strata. Kathmandu valley urban is included as a separate stratum as it’s characteristics differ from the rest. Each stratum was a separate domain. The sample of household was selected in two stages. Within each stratum, at the first sampling stage a specified number of census enumerations areas (EA), was selected systematically with probability proportional to size. A household listing was carried out within the selected enumeration areas, identifying the households with and without children under 5 years. In total, 25 households with and without children under 5 were selected in each sample enumeration area through systematic random sampling method. To ensure strong representativeness of children under 5 in the sample, household with children under 5 were oversampled. Where 13 households with children under 5 and 12 households without were selected from listing in each enumeration area. A total sample of 512 enumeration area and 12800 households was selected for the survey. As the sample is not self-weighting, sample weights are used for reporting survey results. </p><p>The sampling frame of Nepal is based on the 2011 National population and Housing Census (NPHC). The census frame is a complete list of all census wards created for the 2011 NPHC. At the time of last census, the urban household population constituted 20% of the total household population. According to the latest changes in the administrative structure, following the federalization of the government, the urban household population increased to 65%. CBS updated the population frame to reflect the current status. In designing the sample for the Nepal MICS, it was very useful to review the sample design and results of the MICS conducted in 2014, documented in the Final Report of that survey. </p><p>Therefore, a multi-stage, stratified cluster sampling approach was used for the selection of the survey sample. The primary sampling units (PSUs) selected at the first stage were the enumeration areas (EAs) defined for the census enumeration. A listing of households was conducted in each sample enumeration area, and a sample of households was selected at the second stage.  </p><p>The questionnaires were based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili and were pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>National official statistical agency that is responsible for conducting, survey and census.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicator aims to measure access to vaccines, including the newly available or underutilized vaccines, at the national level. For monitoring diseases control and impact of vaccines it is important to measure coverage from each vaccine in national immunization.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The calculation of this indicator requires to have reliable information on total number of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations. The quality of such information is heavily dependent on the questionnaire design, the sample size and design and the accuracy of respondents&#39; answers.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicators is calculated by dividing the total number of children who at the age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations the total number of women aged 15-49 years with a live birth in the same period multiplied by 100.  </p><p>Proportion of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations at any time before survey = Number of children age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations/ Total number of children age 12-23 months ×100</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>For the daily monitoring of field work, team supervisors were responsible. Re-interviewing on one household per cluster was mandatory. Skills and performance of interviewer were observed daily.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ADJUSTMENT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="IMPUTATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REG_AGG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics is the official agency to conducts survey and census. It has trained manpower</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The data is available by province and rural and urban.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows MICS 6 guidelines of UNICEF and can be compared across countries.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS), 2020. Nepal Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2019, Survey Findings Report. Kathmandu, Nepal: Central Bureau of Statistics and UNICEF Nepal.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="46d1aaa7-99d5-4db6-b411-77b4662127a0">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_ACS_HPV</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>NP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3 Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.b Support the research and development of vaccines and medicines for the communicable and non-communicable diseases that primarily affect developing countries, provide access to affordable essential medicines and vaccines, in accordance with the Doha Declaration on the TRIPS Agreement and Public Health, which affirms the right of developing countries to use to the full the provisions in the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights regarding flexibilities to protect public health, and, in particular, provide access to medicines for all</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.b.1 Proportion of the target population covered by all vaccines included in their national programme</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This is under SDG 3</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>15 December 2020</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Household survey section</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>+977 01 4229406</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Thapathali, Kathmandu, Nepal</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>info@cbs.gov.np</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicator shows the percentage of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations at any time before the survey.</p><p>According to WHO, immunisation is a proven tool for controlling and eliminating life-threatening infectious diseases and is estimated to avert between 2 to 3 million death each year. Furthermore, it is one of the most cost-effective health investment, with proven strategies that make it accessible to even the most hard-to-reach and vulnerable populations.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Percentage</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CLASS_SYSTEM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Global MICS guidelines by UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The Global MICS Programme was developed by UNICEF in the 1990s as an international multi-purpose household survey programme to support countries in collecting internationally comparable data on a wide range of indicators on the situation of children and women. It measures key indicators that allow countries to generate data for use in policies and programmes, and to monitor progress towards the national goals and global commitments.</p><p>With the completion of three tier of election, Nepal has been transitioning to the federal system from the Unitary system of Government since 2017. Most notable change is the extensive reclassification of geographical locations from rural to urban at the ward level. New municipalities have been declared and old municipalities either been upgraded to sub-metro city or been extended in area by merging several old wards.</p><p>The new structure of Nepal is divided into seven provinces seven provinces (states). The demarcation of the provinces follows districts, Rukum and Nawalparasi, were split into two separate provinces. The districts are divided into urban and rural locations, which are in turn divided into wards. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The sample for the Nepal MICS 2019 was designed to provide estimates for a large number of indicators on the situation of children and women at the national level, for urban and rural areas and seven provinces. The urban and rural areas within each province were identified as the main sampling strata. Kathmandu valley urban is included as a separate stratum as it’s characteristics differ from the rest. Each stratum was a separate domain. The sample of household was selected in two stages. Within each stratum, at the first sampling stage a specified number of census enumerations areas (EA), was selected systematically with probability proportional to size. A household listing was carried out within the selected enumeration areas, identifying the households with and without children under 5 years. In total, 25 households with and without children under 5 were selected in each sample enumeration area through systematic random sampling method. To ensure strong representativeness of children under 5 in the sample, household with children under 5 were oversampled. Where 13 households with children under 5 and 12 households without were selected from listing in each enumeration area. A total sample of 512 enumeration area and 12800 households was selected for the survey. As the sample is not self-weighting, sample weights are used for reporting survey results. </p><p>The sampling frame of Nepal is based on the 2011 National population and Housing Census (NPHC). The census frame is a complete list of all census wards created for the 2011 NPHC. At the time of last census, the urban household population constituted 20% of the total household population. According to the latest changes in the administrative structure, following the federalization of the government, the urban household population increased to 65%. CBS updated the population frame to reflect the current status. In designing the sample for the Nepal MICS, it was very useful to review the sample design and results of the MICS conducted in 2014, documented in the Final Report of that survey. </p><p>Therefore, a multi-stage, stratified cluster sampling approach was used for the selection of the survey sample. The primary sampling units (PSUs) selected at the first stage were the enumeration areas (EAs) defined for the census enumeration. A listing of households was conducted in each sample enumeration area, and a sample of households was selected at the second stage.  </p><p>The questionnaires were based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili and were pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>National official statistical agency that is responsible for conducting, survey and census.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicator aims to measure access to vaccines, including the newly available or underutilized vaccines, at the national level. For monitoring diseases control and impact of vaccines it is important to measure coverage from each vaccine in national immunization.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The calculation of this indicator requires to have reliable information on total number of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations. The quality of such information is heavily dependent on the questionnaire design, the sample size and design and the accuracy of respondents&#39; answers.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicators is calculated by dividing the total number of children who at the age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations the total number of women aged 15-49 years with a live birth in the same period multiplied by 100.  </p><p>Proportion of children who at age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations at any time before survey = Number of children age 12-23 months had received all basic vaccinations/ Total number of children age 12-23 months ×100</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>For the daily monitoring of field work, team supervisors were responsible. Re-interviewing on one household per cluster was mandatory. Skills and performance of interviewer were observed daily.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ADJUSTMENT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="IMPUTATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REG_AGG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics is the official agency to conducts survey and census. It has trained manpower</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The data is available by province and rural and urban.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows MICS 6 guidelines of UNICEF and can be compared across countries.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS), 2020. Nepal Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2019, Survey Findings Report. Kathmandu, Nepal: Central Bureau of Statistics and UNICEF Nepal.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="d7135440-85ae-4299-bdf0-97d22c6fa808">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_DYN_NMRT</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>NP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3 Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.1  By 2030, end preventable deaths of new-borns and children under 5 years of age, with all countries aiming to reduce neonatal mortality to at least as low as 12 per 1,000 live births and under-5 mortality to at least as low as 25 per 1,000 live births</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.2.2 Neonatal mortality rate</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This is under SDG 3</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>15 December 2020</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Gender and Social Statistics Section</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>+977 01 4229406</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Thapathali, Kathmandu, Nepal</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>info@cbs.gov.np</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>According to UN, the neonatal mortality rate is defined as “the probability that a child born in a specific year or period will die during the first 28 completed days of life if subject to age-specific mortality rates of that period, expressed per 1000 live births.”</p><p>Neonatal deaths (deaths among live births during the first 28 completed days of life) may be subdivided into early neonatal deaths, occurring during the first 7 days of life, and late neonatal deaths, occurring after the 7th day but before the 28th completed day of life.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Deaths per 1000 live births</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CLASS_SYSTEM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Global MICS guidelines by UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>An international multi-purpose household survey programme was developed by UNICEF in the 1990s to support countries in collecting internationally comparable data on a wide range of indicators on the situation of children and women, widely known as global MICS programme. It measures key indicators that allows countries to generate data for using in policy making and designing programs, and to monitor progress towards the national goals and global commitments.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The sample for the Nepal MICS 2019 was designed to provide estimates for a large number of indicators on the situation of children and women at the national level, for urban and rural areas and seven provinces. The urban and rural areas within each province were identified as the main sampling strata. Kathmandu valley urban is included as a separate stratum as it’s characteristics differ from the rest. Each stratum was a separate domain. The sample of household was selected in two stages. Within each stratum, at the first sampling stage a specified number of census enumerations areas (EA), was selected systematically with probability proportional to size. A household listing was carried out within the selected enumeration areas, identifying the households with and without children under 5 years. In total, 25 households with and without children under 5 were selected in each sample enumeration area through systematic random sampling method. To ensure strong representativeness of children under 5 in the sample, household with children under 5 were oversampled. Where 13 households with children under 5 and 12 households without were selected from listing in each enumeration area. A total sample of 512 enumeration area and 12800 households was selected for the survey. As the sample is not self-weighting, sample weights are used for reporting survey results. </p><p>The sampling frame of Nepal is based on the 2011 National population and Housing Census (NPHC). The census frame is a complete list of all census wards created for the 2011 NPHC. At the time of last census, the urban household population constituted 20% of the total household population. According to the latest changes in the administrative structure, following the federalization of the government, the urban household population increased to 65%. CBS updated the population frame to reflect the current status. In designing the sample for the Nepal MICS, it was very useful to review the sample design and results of the MICS conducted in 2014, documented in the Final Report of that survey. </p><p>Therefore, a multi-stage, stratified cluster sampling approach was used for the selection of the survey sample. The primary sampling units (PSUs) selected at the first stage were the enumeration areas (EAs) defined for the census enumeration. A listing of households was conducted in each sample enumeration area, and a sample of households was selected at the second stage.  </p><p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>National official statistical agency that is responsible for conducting, survey and census.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p> Mortality rates among young children are a key output indicator for child health and well-being, and, more broadly, for social and economic development. It is a closely watched public health indicator because it reflects the access of children and communities to basic health interventions such as vaccination, medical treatment of infectious diseases and adequate nutrition.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The calculation of this indicator requires to have reliable information death during the first 28 days of life (0-27 days) and total live births in given period of time. The quality of such information is heavily dependent on the questionnaire design, the sample size and design and the accuracy of respondents&#39; answers.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicators is calculated by dividing the total number of death during the first 28 days of life (0-27 days) by the total number of live births in the same period multiplied by 1000.  </p><p>Neonatal mortality rate = Total number of deaths during the first 28 days of life (0-27 days) in the given period /Total number live births given period ×1000</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ADJUSTMENT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="IMPUTATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REG_AGG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics is the official agency to conducts survey and census. It has trained manpower</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The data is available by province and rural and urban.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows MICS 6 guidelines of UNICEF and can be compared across countries.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS), 2020. Nepal Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2019, Survey Findings Report. Kathmandu, Nepal: Central Bureau of Statistics and UNICEF Nepal.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="38e59ba1-d8e7-4a33-b4e4-98d501fb698d">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_DYN_NMRTN</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>NP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3 Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.1  By 2030, end preventable deaths of new-borns and children under 5 years of age, with all countries aiming to reduce neonatal mortality to at least as low as 12 per 1,000 live births and under-5 mortality to at least as low as 25 per 1,000 live births</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.2.2 Neonatal mortality rate</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This is under SDG 3</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>15 December 2020</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Gender and Social Statistics Section</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>+977 01 4229406</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Thapathali, Kathmandu, Nepal</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>info@cbs.gov.np</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>According to UN, the neonatal mortality rate is defined as “the probability that a child born in a specific year or period will die during the first 28 completed days of life if subject to age-specific mortality rates of that period, expressed per 1000 live births.”</p><p>Neonatal deaths (deaths among live births during the first 28 completed days of life) may be subdivided into early neonatal deaths, occurring during the first 7 days of life, and late neonatal deaths, occurring after the 7th day but before the 28th completed day of life.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Deaths per 1000 live births</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CLASS_SYSTEM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Global MICS guidelines by UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>An international multi-purpose household survey programme was developed by UNICEF in the 1990s to support countries in collecting internationally comparable data on a wide range of indicators on the situation of children and women, widely known as global MICS programme. It measures key indicators that allows countries to generate data for using in policy making and designing programs, and to monitor progress towards the national goals and global commitments.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The sample for the Nepal MICS 2019 was designed to provide estimates for a large number of indicators on the situation of children and women at the national level, for urban and rural areas and seven provinces. The urban and rural areas within each province were identified as the main sampling strata. Kathmandu valley urban is included as a separate stratum as it’s characteristics differ from the rest. Each stratum was a separate domain. The sample of household was selected in two stages. Within each stratum, at the first sampling stage a specified number of census enumerations areas (EA), was selected systematically with probability proportional to size. A household listing was carried out within the selected enumeration areas, identifying the households with and without children under 5 years. In total, 25 households with and without children under 5 were selected in each sample enumeration area through systematic random sampling method. To ensure strong representativeness of children under 5 in the sample, household with children under 5 were oversampled. Where 13 households with children under 5 and 12 households without were selected from listing in each enumeration area. A total sample of 512 enumeration area and 12800 households was selected for the survey. As the sample is not self-weighting, sample weights are used for reporting survey results. </p><p>The sampling frame of Nepal is based on the 2011 National population and Housing Census (NPHC). The census frame is a complete list of all census wards created for the 2011 NPHC. At the time of last census, the urban household population constituted 20% of the total household population. According to the latest changes in the administrative structure, following the federalization of the government, the urban household population increased to 65%. CBS updated the population frame to reflect the current status. In designing the sample for the Nepal MICS, it was very useful to review the sample design and results of the MICS conducted in 2014, documented in the Final Report of that survey. </p><p>Therefore, a multi-stage, stratified cluster sampling approach was used for the selection of the survey sample. The primary sampling units (PSUs) selected at the first stage were the enumeration areas (EAs) defined for the census enumeration. A listing of households was conducted in each sample enumeration area, and a sample of households was selected at the second stage.  </p><p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>National official statistical agency that is responsible for conducting, survey and census.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p> Mortality rates among young children are a key output indicator for child health and well-being, and, more broadly, for social and economic development. It is a closely watched public health indicator because it reflects the access of children and communities to basic health interventions such as vaccination, medical treatment of infectious diseases and adequate nutrition.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The calculation of this indicator requires to have reliable information death during the first 28 days of life (0-27 days) and total live births in given period of time. The quality of such information is heavily dependent on the questionnaire design, the sample size and design and the accuracy of respondents&#39; answers.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicators is calculated by dividing the total number of death during the first 28 days of life (0-27 days) by the total number of live births in the same period multiplied by 1000.  </p><p>Neonatal mortality rate = Total number of deaths during the first 28 days of life (0-27 days) in the given period /Total number live births given period ×1000</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ADJUSTMENT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="IMPUTATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REG_AGG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics is the official agency to conducts survey and census. It has trained manpower</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The data is available by province and rural and urban.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows MICS 6 guidelines of UNICEF and can be compared across countries.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS), 2020. Nepal Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2019, Survey Findings Report. Kathmandu, Nepal: Central Bureau of Statistics and UNICEF Nepal.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="e60aa6cc-68be-4e2e-b915-71a26c786b8e">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SP_DYN_ADKL</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>NP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3 Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.7 By 2030, ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health-care services, including for family planning, information and education, and the integration of reproductive health into national strategies and programmes</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.7.2 Adolescent birth rate (aged 10-14 years; aged 15-19 years) per 1,000 women in that age group</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This is under SDG 3</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>15 December 2020</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Gender and Social Statistics  Section</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>+977 01 4229406</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Thapathali, Kathmandu, Nepal</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>info@cbs.gov.np</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>According to WHO, the adolescent birth rate is technically known as the age-specific fertility rate. It provides a basic measure of reproductive health focusing on a vulnerable group of adolescent women. The indicators ‘Adolescent birth rate (aged 10-14 years; aged 15-19 years) per 1,000 women in that age group’ is defined as annual number of births to women  between the age group 10-14 and 15-19 years per 1000 women in that age group.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Annual number of births to females aged 10-14 or 15-19 years per 1,000 females in the respective age group</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CLASS_SYSTEM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Global MICS guidelines by UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>An international multi-purpose household survey programme was developed by UNICEF in the 1990s to support countries in collecting internationally comparable data on a wide range of indicators on the situation of children and women, widely known as global MICS programme. It measures key indicators that allows countries to generate data for using in policy making and designing programs, and to monitor progress towards the national goals and global commitments.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The sample for the Nepal MICS 2019 was designed to provide estimates for a large number of indicators on the situation of children and women at the national level, for urban and rural areas and seven provinces. The urban and rural areas within each province were identified as the main sampling strata. Kathmandu valley urban is included as a separate stratum as it’s characteristics differ from the rest. Each stratum was a separate domain. The sample of household was selected in two stages. Within each stratum, at the first sampling stage a specified number of census enumerations areas (EA), was selected systematically with probability proportional to size. A household listing was carried out within the selected enumeration areas, identifying the households with and without children under 5 years. In total, 25 households with and without children under 5 were selected in each sample enumeration area through systematic random sampling method. To ensure strong representativeness of children under 5 in the sample, household with children under 5 were oversampled. Where 13 households with children under 5 and 12 households without were selected from listing in each enumeration area. A total sample of 512 enumeration area and 12800 households was selected for the survey. As the sample is not self-weighting, sample weights are used for reporting survey results. </p><p>The sampling frame of Nepal is based on the 2011 National population and Housing Census (NPHC). The census frame is a complete list of all census wards created for the 2011 NPHC. At the time of last census, the urban household population constituted 20% of the total household population. According to the latest changes in the administrative structure, following the federalization of the government, the urban household population increased to 65%. CBS updated the population frame to reflect the current status. In designing the sample for the Nepal MICS, it was very useful to review the sample design and results of the MICS conducted in 2014, documented in the Final Report of that survey. </p><p>Therefore, a multi-stage, stratified cluster sampling approach was used for the selection of the survey sample. The primary sampling units (PSUs) selected at the first stage were the enumeration areas (EAs) defined for the census enumeration. A listing of households was conducted in each sample enumeration area, and a sample of households was selected at the second stage.  </p><p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>National official statistical agency that is responsible for conducting, survey and census.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p> For the improvement of sexual and reproductive health and the social and economic well-being of adolescents, rate of adolescent fertility must be reduced and address the multiple factors underlying it. Early pregnancy and child birth has greater risks of complications or even death during pregnancy and birth. Furthermore, mother and children are subject to be more vulnerable. Therefore, preventing births very early in a woman’s life is an important measure to improve maternal health and reduce the infant mortality rate. The adolescent birth rate also provides indirect evidence on access to pertinent health services since young people, and in a particular unmarried adolescent women, often experience difficulties in access to sexual and reproductive health services.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The calculation of this indicator requires to have reliable information on number of live births to women aged 15-19 years. The quality of such information is heavily dependent on the questionnaire design, the sample size and design and the accuracy of respondents&#39; answers.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The adolescent birth rate is computed as a ratio. The numerator is the number of live births to women aged 15-19 years, and the denominator an estimate of exposure to childbearing by women aged 15-19 years. The computation is the same for the age group 10-14 years. The numerator and the denominator are calculated differently for civil registration, survey and census data.</p><p>Age – specific fertility rates = Number of births to women in age group in a given year or reference period /Number of person-years of exposure in age group a during the specified reference ×100</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ADJUSTMENT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="IMPUTATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REG_AGG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics is the official agency to conducts survey and census. It has trained manpower</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The data is available by province and rural and urban.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows MICS 6 guidelines of UNICEF and can be compared across countries.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS), 2020. Nepal Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2019, Survey Findings Report. Kathmandu, Nepal: Central Bureau of Statistics and UNICEF Nepal.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="fe5d3690-0f9a-4420-9fe7-3edef435b202">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_FPL_MTMM</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>NP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3 Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.7 By 2030, ensure universal access to sexual and reproductive health-care services, including for family planning, information and education, and the integration of reproductive health into national strategies and programmes</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.7.1 Proportion of women of reproductive age (aged 15-49 years) who have their need for family planning satisfied with modern methods</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This is under SDG 3</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>15 December 2020</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Gender and Social Statistics Section</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>+977 01 4229406</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Thapathali, Kathmandu, Nepal</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>info@cbs.gov.np</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>WHO defines the indicator proportion of women of reproductive age  (aged 15-49 years) who have their need for family planning satisfies with modern methods as the percentage of women of reproductive age (15-49 years) who desire either to have no (additional) children or to postpone the next child and who are currently using a modern method of contraception. </p><p>This indicator has two components i.e. contraceptive prevalence (any method and modern methods) and unmet need for family planning. The percentage of women who are currently using, or whose partner is currently using, at least one method of contraception, regardless of method use. Contraceptive methods are classified as either modern or traditional. Female and male sterilization, intra-uterine device (IUD), implant, injectable, oral contraceptive pills, condoms, vaginal barrier, lactation amenorrhea method (LAM), emergency contraception and other modern methods not reported separately falls under modern contraceptive methods.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Percentage</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CLASS_SYSTEM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Global MICS guidelines by UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>An international multi-purpose household survey programme was developed by UNICEF in the 1990s to support countries in collecting internationally comparable data on a wide range of indicators on the situation of children and women, widely known as global MICS programme. It measures key indicators that allows countries to generate data for using in policy making and designing programs, and to monitor progress towards the national goals and global commitments.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The sample for the Nepal MICS 2019 was designed to provide estimates for a large number of indicators on the situation of children and women at the national level, for urban and rural areas and seven provinces. The urban and rural areas within each province were identified as the main sampling strata. Kathmandu valley urban is included as a separate stratum as it’s characteristics differ from the rest. Each stratum was a separate domain. The sample of household was selected in two stages. Within each stratum, at the first sampling stage a specified number of census enumerations areas (EA), was selected systematically with probability proportional to size. A household listing was carried out within the selected enumeration areas, identifying the households with and without children under 5 years. In total, 25 households with and without children under 5 were selected in each sample enumeration area through systematic random sampling method. To ensure strong representativeness of children under 5 in the sample, household with children under 5 were oversampled. Where 13 households with children under 5 and 12 households without were selected from listing in each enumeration area. A total sample of 512 enumeration area and 12800 households was selected for the survey. As the sample is not self-weighting, sample weights are used for reporting survey results. </p><p>The sampling frame of Nepal is based on the 2011 National population and Housing Census (NPHC). The census frame is a complete list of all census wards created for the 2011 NPHC. At the time of last census, the urban household population constituted 20% of the total household population. According to the latest changes in the administrative structure, following the federalization of the government, the urban household population increased to 65%. CBS updated the population frame to reflect the current status. In designing the sample for the Nepal MICS, it was very useful to review the sample design and results of the MICS conducted in 2014, documented in the Final Report of that survey. </p><p>Therefore, a multi-stage, stratified cluster sampling approach was used for the selection of the survey sample. The primary sampling units (PSUs) selected at the first stage were the enumeration areas (EAs) defined for the census enumeration. A listing of households was conducted in each sample enumeration area, and a sample of households was selected at the second stage.  </p><p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>National official statistical agency that is responsible for conducting, survey and census.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p> To assess overall levels of coverage of family planning programmes and services, the indicator proportion of women of reproductive age (aged 15-49 years) who have their need for family planning satisfied with modern method is very useful. Access to and use of an effective means to prevent pregnancy helps enable women and their partners to exercise their rights to decide freely and responsibly the number and spacing of their children and to have the information, education and means to do so. Meeting demand for family planning with modern methods also contributes to maternal and child health by preventing unintended pregnancies and closely spaced pregnancies, which are at higher risk for poor obstetrical outcomes. Levels of demand for family planning satisfied with modern methods of 75 per cent or more are generally considered high, and values of 50 per cent or less are generally considered as very low.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The calculation of this indicator requires to have reliable information on women who are currently using a modern method of contraception and number of women using any method of contraception or are having an unmet need for family planning. The quality of such information is heavily dependent on the questionnaire design, the sample size and design and the accuracy of respondents&#39; answers.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The numerator is the percentage of women of reproductive age (15-49 years old) who are currently using, or whose partner is currently using, at least one modern contraceptive method. The denominator is the total demand for family planning (the sum of contraceptive prevalence (any method) and the unmet need for family planning).</p><p>Proportion of women of reproductive age (aged 15-49 years) who have their need for family planning satisfied with modern methods = Number of women who are currently using a modern of contraception /Number of women who are using any method of contraception or are having an unmet need for family planning ×100</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ADJUSTMENT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="IMPUTATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REG_AGG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics is the official agency to conducts survey and census. It has trained manpower</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The data is available by province and rural and urban.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows MICS 6 guidelines of UNICEF and can be compared across countries.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS), 2020. Nepal Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2019, Survey Findings Report. Kathmandu, Nepal: Central Bureau of Statistics and UNICEF Nepal.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="be31dc40-f0da-4fcb-b974-b7cbf7117103">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_DYN_IMRT</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>NP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3 Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.1  By 2030, end preventable deaths of new-borns and children under 5 years of age, with all countries aiming to reduce neonatal mortality to at least as low as 12 per 1,000 live births and under-5 mortality to at least as low as 25 per 1,000 live births</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.2.1 Under-five mortality rate</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This is under SDG 3</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>15 December 2020</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Gender and Social Statistics Section</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>+977 01 4229406</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Thapathali, Kathmandu, Nepal</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>info@cbs.gov.np</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>According to WHO, under age 5 mortality rate is defined as the probability of a child born in a given year dying before reaching their fifth birthday and expressed per 1000 live birth.</p><p>According to United Nations Principles and Recommendations for a Vital Statistics System live birth is defined as the complete expulsion or extraction from its mother of a product of conception, irrespective of the duration of pregnancy, which after such separation breathes or shows any other evidence of life such as beating of the heart, pulsation of the umbilical cord, definite movement of voluntary muscles, whether or not the umbilical cord has been cut or the placenta is attached; each product of such a birth is considered as live-born regardless of gestational age.</p><p>Death is permanent is the permanent disappearance of all evidence of life at any time after live birth has taken place (post-natal cessation of vital functions without capability of resuscitation)</p><p>Under-five mortality captures the effect of gender discrimination better than infant mortality does, as malnutrition and medical interventions have more significant impacts to this age group. If female under-five mortality is higher, girls are likely to have less access to resources than boys.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Number of deaths per 1000 live births</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CLASS_SYSTEM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Global MICS guidelines by UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>An international multi-purpose household survey programme was developed by UNICEF in the 1990s to support countries in collecting internationally comparable data on a wide range of indicators on the situation of children and women, widely known as global MICS programme. It measures key indicators that allows countries to generate data for using in policy making and designing programs, and to monitor progress towards the national goals and global commitments.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The sample for the Nepal MICS 2019 was designed to provide estimates for a large number of indicators on the situation of children and women at the national level, for urban and rural areas and seven provinces. The urban and rural areas within each province were identified as the main sampling strata. Kathmandu valley urban is included as a separate stratum as it’s characteristics differ from the rest. Each stratum was a separate domain. The sample of household was selected in two stages. Within each stratum, at the first sampling stage a specified number of census enumerations areas (EA), was selected systematically with probability proportional to size. A household listing was carried out within the selected enumeration areas, identifying the households with and without children under 5 years. In total, 25 households with and without children under 5 were selected in each sample enumeration area through systematic random sampling method. To ensure strong representativeness of children under 5 in the sample, household with children under 5 were oversampled. Where 13 households with children under 5 and 12 households without were selected from listing in each enumeration area. A total sample of 512 enumeration area and 12800 households was selected for the survey. As the sample is not self-weighting, sample weights are used for reporting survey results. </p><p>The sampling frame of Nepal is based on the 2011 National population and Housing Census (NPHC). The census frame is a complete list of all census wards created for the 2011 NPHC. At the time of last census, the urban household population constituted 20% of the total household population. According to the latest changes in the administrative structure, following the federalization of the government, the urban household population increased to 65%. CBS updated the population frame to reflect the current status. In designing the sample for the Nepal MICS, it was very useful to review the sample design and results of the MICS conducted in 2014, documented in the Final Report of that survey. </p><p>Therefore, a multi-stage, stratified cluster sampling approach was used for the selection of the survey sample. The primary sampling units (PSUs) selected at the first stage were the enumeration areas (EAs) defined for the census enumeration. A listing of households was conducted in each sample enumeration area, and a sample of households was selected at the second stage.  </p><p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p> 2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>National official statistical agency that is responsible for conducting, survey and census.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p> Child survival is measured by under-five mortality rate. Also, it reflects the social, economic and environment conditions in which (and others in society) live, including their health care. Because data on the incidences and prevalence of disease (morbidity data) frequently are unavailable, mortality rates are often used to identify vulnerable populations. Furthermore, it also helps to measure the access of children and communities to basic health intervention such as vaccination, medical treatment of infectious disease and adequate nutrition.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The calculation of this indicator requires to have reliable information on total deaths of children under 5 years and total live births in given period of time. The quality of such information is heavily dependent on the questionnaire design, the sample size and design and the accuracy of respondents&#39; answers.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicators is calculated by dividing the total number deaths of children under 5 years by the total number of live births in the same period multiplied by 1000.  </p><p>Under 5 mortality rate = Number of deaths of children under 5 years in given period of time /Total number live births in given period of time×1000</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ADJUSTMENT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="IMPUTATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REG_AGG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics is the official agency to conducts survey and census. It has trained manpower</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The data is available by province and rural and urban.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows MICS 6 guidelines of UNICEF and can be compared across countries.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS), 2020. Nepal Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2019, Survey Findings Report. Kathmandu, Nepal: Central Bureau of Statistics and UNICEF Nepal.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="988195e9-85c6-44cd-8bc3-3b2bcf848d37">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_DYN_IMRTN</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>NP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3 Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.1  By 2030, end preventable deaths of new-borns and children under 5 years of age, with all countries aiming to reduce neonatal mortality to at least as low as 12 per 1,000 live births and under-5 mortality to at least as low as 25 per 1,000 live births</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.2.1 Under-five mortality rate</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This is under SDG 3</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>15 December 2020</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Gender and Social Statistics Section</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>+977 01 4229406</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Thapathali, Kathmandu, Nepal</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>info@cbs.gov.np</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>According to WHO, under age 5 mortality rate is defined as the probability of a child born in a given year dying before reaching their fifth birthday and expressed per 1000 live birth.</p><p>According to United Nations Principles and Recommendations for a Vital Statistics System live birth is defined as the complete expulsion or extraction from its mother of a product of conception, irrespective of the duration of pregnancy, which after such separation breathes or shows any other evidence of life such as beating of the heart, pulsation of the umbilical cord, definite movement of voluntary muscles, whether or not the umbilical cord has been cut or the placenta is attached; each product of such a birth is considered as live-born regardless of gestational age.</p><p>Death is permanent is the permanent disappearance of all evidence of life at any time after live birth has taken place (post-natal cessation of vital functions without capability of resuscitation)</p><p>Under-five mortality captures the effect of gender discrimination better than infant mortality does, as malnutrition and medical interventions have more significant impacts to this age group. If female under-five mortality is higher, girls are likely to have less access to resources than boys.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Number of deaths per 1000 live births</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CLASS_SYSTEM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Global MICS guidelines by UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>An international multi-purpose household survey programme was developed by UNICEF in the 1990s to support countries in collecting internationally comparable data on a wide range of indicators on the situation of children and women, widely known as global MICS programme. It measures key indicators that allows countries to generate data for using in policy making and designing programs, and to monitor progress towards the national goals and global commitments.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The sample for the Nepal MICS 2019 was designed to provide estimates for a large number of indicators on the situation of children and women at the national level, for urban and rural areas and seven provinces. The urban and rural areas within each province were identified as the main sampling strata. Kathmandu valley urban is included as a separate stratum as it’s characteristics differ from the rest. Each stratum was a separate domain. The sample of household was selected in two stages. Within each stratum, at the first sampling stage a specified number of census enumerations areas (EA), was selected systematically with probability proportional to size. A household listing was carried out within the selected enumeration areas, identifying the households with and without children under 5 years. In total, 25 households with and without children under 5 were selected in each sample enumeration area through systematic random sampling method. To ensure strong representativeness of children under 5 in the sample, household with children under 5 were oversampled. Where 13 households with children under 5 and 12 households without were selected from listing in each enumeration area. A total sample of 512 enumeration area and 12800 households was selected for the survey. As the sample is not self-weighting, sample weights are used for reporting survey results. </p><p>The sampling frame of Nepal is based on the 2011 National population and Housing Census (NPHC). The census frame is a complete list of all census wards created for the 2011 NPHC. At the time of last census, the urban household population constituted 20% of the total household population. According to the latest changes in the administrative structure, following the federalization of the government, the urban household population increased to 65%. CBS updated the population frame to reflect the current status. In designing the sample for the Nepal MICS, it was very useful to review the sample design and results of the MICS conducted in 2014, documented in the Final Report of that survey. </p><p>Therefore, a multi-stage, stratified cluster sampling approach was used for the selection of the survey sample. The primary sampling units (PSUs) selected at the first stage were the enumeration areas (EAs) defined for the census enumeration. A listing of households was conducted in each sample enumeration area, and a sample of households was selected at the second stage.  </p><p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p> 2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>National official statistical agency that is responsible for conducting, survey and census.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p> Child survival is measured by under-five mortality rate. Also, it reflects the social, economic and environment conditions in which (and others in society) live, including their health care. Because data on the incidences and prevalence of disease (morbidity data) frequently are unavailable, mortality rates are often used to identify vulnerable populations. Furthermore, it also helps to measure the access of children and communities to basic health intervention such as vaccination, medical treatment of infectious disease and adequate nutrition.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The calculation of this indicator requires to have reliable information on total deaths of children under 5 years and total live births in given period of time. The quality of such information is heavily dependent on the questionnaire design, the sample size and design and the accuracy of respondents&#39; answers.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicators is calculated by dividing the total number deaths of children under 5 years by the total number of live births in the same period multiplied by 1000.  </p><p>Under 5 mortality rate = Number of deaths of children under 5 years in given period of time /Total number live births in given period of time×1000</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ADJUSTMENT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="IMPUTATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REG_AGG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics is the official agency to conducts survey and census. It has trained manpower</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The data is available by province and rural and urban.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows MICS 6 guidelines of UNICEF and can be compared across countries.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS), 2020. Nepal Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2019, Survey Findings Report. Kathmandu, Nepal: Central Bureau of Statistics and UNICEF Nepal.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="b30961c8-989e-4394-9877-4716e48da3d5">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_DYN_MORT</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>NP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3 Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.1  By 2030, end preventable deaths of new-borns and children under 5 years of age, with all countries aiming to reduce neonatal mortality to at least as low as 12 per 1,000 live births and under-5 mortality to at least as low as 25 per 1,000 live births</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.2.1 Under-five mortality rate</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This is under SDG 3</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>15 December 2020</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Gender and Social Statistics Section</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>+977 01 4229406</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Thapathali, Kathmandu, Nepal</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>info@cbs.gov.np</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>According to WHO, under age 5 mortality rate is defined as the probability of a child born in a given year dying before reaching their fifth birthday and expressed per 1000 live birth.</p><p>According to United Nations Principles and Recommendations for a Vital Statistics System live birth is defined as the complete expulsion or extraction from its mother of a product of conception, irrespective of the duration of pregnancy, which after such separation breathes or shows any other evidence of life such as beating of the heart, pulsation of the umbilical cord, definite movement of voluntary muscles, whether or not the umbilical cord has been cut or the placenta is attached; each product of such a birth is considered as live-born regardless of gestational age.</p><p>Death is permanent is the permanent disappearance of all evidence of life at any time after live birth has taken place (post-natal cessation of vital functions without capability of resuscitation)</p><p>Under-five mortality captures the effect of gender discrimination better than infant mortality does, as malnutrition and medical interventions have more significant impacts to this age group. If female under-five mortality is higher, girls are likely to have less access to resources than boys.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Number of deaths per 1000 live births</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CLASS_SYSTEM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Global MICS guidelines by UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>An international multi-purpose household survey programme was developed by UNICEF in the 1990s to support countries in collecting internationally comparable data on a wide range of indicators on the situation of children and women, widely known as global MICS programme. It measures key indicators that allows countries to generate data for using in policy making and designing programs, and to monitor progress towards the national goals and global commitments.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The sample for the Nepal MICS 2019 was designed to provide estimates for a large number of indicators on the situation of children and women at the national level, for urban and rural areas and seven provinces. The urban and rural areas within each province were identified as the main sampling strata. Kathmandu valley urban is included as a separate stratum as it’s characteristics differ from the rest. Each stratum was a separate domain. The sample of household was selected in two stages. Within each stratum, at the first sampling stage a specified number of census enumerations areas (EA), was selected systematically with probability proportional to size. A household listing was carried out within the selected enumeration areas, identifying the households with and without children under 5 years. In total, 25 households with and without children under 5 were selected in each sample enumeration area through systematic random sampling method. To ensure strong representativeness of children under 5 in the sample, household with children under 5 were oversampled. Where 13 households with children under 5 and 12 households without were selected from listing in each enumeration area. A total sample of 512 enumeration area and 12800 households was selected for the survey. As the sample is not self-weighting, sample weights are used for reporting survey results. </p><p>The sampling frame of Nepal is based on the 2011 National population and Housing Census (NPHC). The census frame is a complete list of all census wards created for the 2011 NPHC. At the time of last census, the urban household population constituted 20% of the total household population. According to the latest changes in the administrative structure, following the federalization of the government, the urban household population increased to 65%. CBS updated the population frame to reflect the current status. In designing the sample for the Nepal MICS, it was very useful to review the sample design and results of the MICS conducted in 2014, documented in the Final Report of that survey. </p><p>Therefore, a multi-stage, stratified cluster sampling approach was used for the selection of the survey sample. The primary sampling units (PSUs) selected at the first stage were the enumeration areas (EAs) defined for the census enumeration. A listing of households was conducted in each sample enumeration area, and a sample of households was selected at the second stage.  </p><p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p> 2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>National official statistical agency that is responsible for conducting, survey and census.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p> Child survival is measured by under-five mortality rate. Also, it reflects the social, economic and environment conditions in which (and others in society) live, including their health care. Because data on the incidences and prevalence of disease (morbidity data) frequently are unavailable, mortality rates are often used to identify vulnerable populations. Furthermore, it also helps to measure the access of children and communities to basic health intervention such as vaccination, medical treatment of infectious disease and adequate nutrition.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The calculation of this indicator requires to have reliable information on total deaths of children under 5 years and total live births in given period of time. The quality of such information is heavily dependent on the questionnaire design, the sample size and design and the accuracy of respondents&#39; answers.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicators is calculated by dividing the total number deaths of children under 5 years by the total number of live births in the same period multiplied by 1000.  </p><p>Under 5 mortality rate = Number of deaths of children under 5 years in given period of time /Total number live births in given period of time×1000</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ADJUSTMENT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="IMPUTATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REG_AGG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics is the official agency to conducts survey and census. It has trained manpower</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The data is available by province and rural and urban.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows MICS 6 guidelines of UNICEF and can be compared across countries.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS), 2020. Nepal Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2019, Survey Findings Report. Kathmandu, Nepal: Central Bureau of Statistics and UNICEF Nepal.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="7d2dc3ad-ff2d-4a33-b0e5-61425cf5dbef">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_DYN_MORTN</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>NP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3 Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.1  By 2030, end preventable deaths of new-borns and children under 5 years of age, with all countries aiming to reduce neonatal mortality to at least as low as 12 per 1,000 live births and under-5 mortality to at least as low as 25 per 1,000 live births</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.2.1 Under-five mortality rate</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This is under SDG 3</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>15 December 2020</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Gender and Social Statistics Section</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>+977 01 4229406</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Thapathali, Kathmandu, Nepal</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>info@cbs.gov.np</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>According to WHO, under age 5 mortality rate is defined as the probability of a child born in a given year dying before reaching their fifth birthday and expressed per 1000 live birth.</p><p>According to United Nations Principles and Recommendations for a Vital Statistics System live birth is defined as the complete expulsion or extraction from its mother of a product of conception, irrespective of the duration of pregnancy, which after such separation breathes or shows any other evidence of life such as beating of the heart, pulsation of the umbilical cord, definite movement of voluntary muscles, whether or not the umbilical cord has been cut or the placenta is attached; each product of such a birth is considered as live-born regardless of gestational age.</p><p>Death is permanent is the permanent disappearance of all evidence of life at any time after live birth has taken place (post-natal cessation of vital functions without capability of resuscitation)</p><p>Under-five mortality captures the effect of gender discrimination better than infant mortality does, as malnutrition and medical interventions have more significant impacts to this age group. If female under-five mortality is higher, girls are likely to have less access to resources than boys.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Number of deaths per 1000 live births</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CLASS_SYSTEM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Global MICS guidelines by UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>An international multi-purpose household survey programme was developed by UNICEF in the 1990s to support countries in collecting internationally comparable data on a wide range of indicators on the situation of children and women, widely known as global MICS programme. It measures key indicators that allows countries to generate data for using in policy making and designing programs, and to monitor progress towards the national goals and global commitments.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The sample for the Nepal MICS 2019 was designed to provide estimates for a large number of indicators on the situation of children and women at the national level, for urban and rural areas and seven provinces. The urban and rural areas within each province were identified as the main sampling strata. Kathmandu valley urban is included as a separate stratum as it’s characteristics differ from the rest. Each stratum was a separate domain. The sample of household was selected in two stages. Within each stratum, at the first sampling stage a specified number of census enumerations areas (EA), was selected systematically with probability proportional to size. A household listing was carried out within the selected enumeration areas, identifying the households with and without children under 5 years. In total, 25 households with and without children under 5 were selected in each sample enumeration area through systematic random sampling method. To ensure strong representativeness of children under 5 in the sample, household with children under 5 were oversampled. Where 13 households with children under 5 and 12 households without were selected from listing in each enumeration area. A total sample of 512 enumeration area and 12800 households was selected for the survey. As the sample is not self-weighting, sample weights are used for reporting survey results. </p><p>The sampling frame of Nepal is based on the 2011 National population and Housing Census (NPHC). The census frame is a complete list of all census wards created for the 2011 NPHC. At the time of last census, the urban household population constituted 20% of the total household population. According to the latest changes in the administrative structure, following the federalization of the government, the urban household population increased to 65%. CBS updated the population frame to reflect the current status. In designing the sample for the Nepal MICS, it was very useful to review the sample design and results of the MICS conducted in 2014, documented in the Final Report of that survey. </p><p>Therefore, a multi-stage, stratified cluster sampling approach was used for the selection of the survey sample. The primary sampling units (PSUs) selected at the first stage were the enumeration areas (EAs) defined for the census enumeration. A listing of households was conducted in each sample enumeration area, and a sample of households was selected at the second stage.  </p><p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p> 2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>National official statistical agency that is responsible for conducting, survey and census.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p> Child survival is measured by under-five mortality rate. Also, it reflects the social, economic and environment conditions in which (and others in society) live, including their health care. Because data on the incidences and prevalence of disease (morbidity data) frequently are unavailable, mortality rates are often used to identify vulnerable populations. Furthermore, it also helps to measure the access of children and communities to basic health intervention such as vaccination, medical treatment of infectious disease and adequate nutrition.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The calculation of this indicator requires to have reliable information on total deaths of children under 5 years and total live births in given period of time. The quality of such information is heavily dependent on the questionnaire design, the sample size and design and the accuracy of respondents&#39; answers.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicators is calculated by dividing the total number deaths of children under 5 years by the total number of live births in the same period multiplied by 1000.  </p><p>Under 5 mortality rate = Number of deaths of children under 5 years in given period of time /Total number live births in given period of time×1000</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ADJUSTMENT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="IMPUTATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REG_AGG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics is the official agency to conducts survey and census. It has trained manpower</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The data is available by province and rural and urban.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows MICS 6 guidelines of UNICEF and can be compared across countries.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS), 2020. Nepal Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2019, Survey Findings Report. Kathmandu, Nepal: Central Bureau of Statistics and UNICEF Nepal.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="172988d5-e69c-4c41-bf46-25358926502f">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_ACS_UNHC</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>NP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3 Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.8 Achieve universal health coverage, including financial risk protection, access to quality essential health-care services and access to safe, effective, quality and affordable essential medicines and vaccines for all</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.8.1 Coverage of essential health services (defined as the average coverage of essential services based on tracer interventions that include reproductive, maternal, newborn and child health, infectious diseases, non-communicable diseases and service capacity and access, among the general and the most disadvantaged population)</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This is under SDG 3</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>15 December 2020</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Household survey section</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>+977 01 4229406</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Thapathali, Kathmandu, Nepal</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>info@cbs.gov.np</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicator shows the percentage of children under age 5 with ARI symptoms in the last 2 weeks for whom advice or treatment was sought from a health facility or provider.</p><p>ARI stands for ‘acute respiratory infection’. The definition of ARI used in the Demographic and Health Surveys (DHS) and in the Multiple Indicator Cluster Surveys (MICS) was chosen by the group and is based on mothers’ perceptions of a child who has a cough, is breathing faster than usual with short, quick breaths or is having difficulty breathing, excluding children that had only a blocked nose.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Percentage</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CLASS_SYSTEM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Global MICS guidelines by UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>An international multi-purpose household survey programme was developed by UNICEF in the 1990s to support countries in collecting internationally comparable data on a wide range of indicators on the situation of children and women, widely known as global MICS programme. It measures key indicators that allows countries to generate data for using in policy making and designing programs, and to monitor progress towards the national goals and global commitments.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The sample for the Nepal MICS 2019 was designed to provide estimates for a large number of indicators on the situation of children and women at the national level, for urban and rural areas and seven provinces. The urban and rural areas within each province were identified as the main sampling strata. Kathmandu valley urban is included as a separate stratum as it’s characteristics differ from the rest. Each stratum was a separate domain. The sample of household was selected in two stages. Within each stratum, at the first sampling stage a specified number of census enumerations areas (EA), was selected systematically with probability proportional to size. A household listing was carried out within the selected enumeration areas, identifying the households with and without children under 5 years. In total, 25 households with and without children under 5 were selected in each sample enumeration area through systematic random sampling method. To ensure strong representativeness of children under 5 in the sample, household with children under 5 were oversampled. Where 13 households with children under 5 and 12 households without were selected from listing in each enumeration area. A total sample of 512 enumeration area and 12800 households was selected for the survey. As the sample is not self-weighting, sample weights are used for reporting survey results. </p><p>The sampling frame of Nepal is based on the 2011 National population and Housing Census (NPHC). The census frame is a complete list of all census wards created for the 2011 NPHC. At the time of last census, the urban household population constituted 20% of the total household population. According to the latest changes in the administrative structure, following the federalization of the government, the urban household population increased to 65%. CBS updated the population frame to reflect the current status. In designing the sample for the Nepal MICS, it was very useful to review the sample design and results of the MICS conducted in 2014, documented in the Final Report of that survey. </p><p>Therefore, a multi-stage, stratified cluster sampling approach was used for the selection of the survey sample. The primary sampling units (PSUs) selected at the first stage were the enumeration areas (EAs) defined for the census enumeration. A listing of households was conducted in each sample enumeration area, and a sample of households was selected at the second stage.  </p><p>The questionnaires were based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili and were pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>National official statistical agency that is responsible for conducting, survey and census.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Appropriate care of the sick child is defined as providers that can correctly diagnose and treat pneumonia. The proportion of under-fives with ARI that are taken to an appropriate health-care provider is therefore a key indicator for coverage of intervention and care-seeking, and provides critical inputs to the monitoring of progress towards child survival-related Millennium Development Goals and Strategies.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The quality of such information is heavily dependent on the questionnaire design, the sample size and design and the accuracy of respondents&#39; answers.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This indicators is calculated by dividing the total number of children aged under 5 years with ARI system by the total number of children aged under 5 years multiplied by 100.  </p><p>Children under age 5 with ARI symptoms = Children aged under 5 years with ARI symptoms/ Total number of children aged under 5 years×100</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>For the daily monitoring of field work, team supervisors were responsible. Re-interviewing on one household per cluster was mandatory. Skills and performance of interviewer were observed daily.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ADJUSTMENT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="IMPUTATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REG_AGG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics is the official agency to conducts survey and census. It has trained manpower</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The data is available by province and rural and urban.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows MICS 6 guidelines of UNICEF and can be compared across countries.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS), 2020. Nepal Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2019, Survey Findings Report. Kathmandu, Nepal: Central Bureau of Statistics and UNICEF Nepal.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
  <mes:MetadataSet structureRef="MDS1" setID="1902d2fa-67ec-4b5a-88d7-34f3f83221ed">
    <com:Name xml:lang="en">SDG METADATA SET</com:Name>
    <gen:Report id="SDG_META_RPT">
      <gen:Target id="KEY_TARGET">
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="DIMENSION_DESCRIPTOR_VALUES_TARGET">
          <gen:DataKey>
            <com:KeyValue id="SERIES">
              <com:Value>SH_PRV_SMOK</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REPORTING_TYPE">
              <com:Value>N</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
            <com:KeyValue id="REF_AREA">
              <com:Value>NP</com:Value>
            </com:KeyValue>
          </gen:DataKey>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
        <gen:ReferenceValue id="Dataflow">
          <gen:ObjectReference>
            <URN>urn:sdmx:org.sdmx.infomodel.datastructure.Dataflow=IAEG-SDGs:DF_SDG_GLC(1.0)</URN>
          </gen:ObjectReference>
        </gen:ReferenceValue>
      </gen:Target>
      <gen:AttributeSet>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_GOAL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3 Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_TARGET">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.a Strengthen the implementation of the World Health Organization Framework Convention on Tobacco Control in all countries, as appropriate</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_INDICATOR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>3.a.1 Age-standardized prevalence of current tobacco use among persons aged 15 years and older </p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_SERIES_DESCR">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>This is under SDG 3</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="META_LAST_UPDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>15 December 2020</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SDG_CUSTODIAN_AGENCIES">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_ORGANISATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_NAME">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ORGANISATION_UNIT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Gender and Social Statistics Section</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_FUNCT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Tirtha Chaulagain, Information Officer</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_PHONE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>+977 01 4229406</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_MAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Thapathali, Kathmandu, Nepal</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CONTACT_EMAIL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>info@cbs.gov.np</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="STAT_CONC_DEF">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The indicator is defined as the percentage of the population aged 15 years and over who currently use any tobacco product (smoked and/or smokeless tobacco) on a daily or non-daily basis.</p><p>Use of smoked and/or smokeless tobacco products is known as tobacco use. </p><p>“Current use” means use of tobacco product within the previous 30 days at the time of survey, whether daily or non-daily use. </p><p>“Smoked tobacco products” include cigarettes, cigarillos, cigars, cheroots, bidis, pipes, shisha (water pipes), roll-your-own tobacco, kretek and any other form of tobacco that is consumed by smoking.</p><p>“Smokeless tobacco product” includes moist snuff, creamy snuff, dry snuff, plug, dissolvable, gul, loose leaf, red tooth powder, snus, chimo, guthkha, khaini, gudakhu, zarda, quiman, dohra, tuibur, nasway, naas, naswar, shammah, toombak, paan (betel quid with tobacco), iq’mink, mishri, tapkeer, tombol and any other tobacco product that consumed by sniffing, holding in the mouth or chewing.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="UNIT_MEASURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Percentage</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="CLASS_SYSTEM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Global MICS guidelines by UNICEF</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="SOURCE_TYPE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>An international multi-purpose household survey programme was developed by UNICEF in the 1990s to support countries in collecting internationally comparable data on a wide range of indicators on the situation of children and women, widely known as global MICS programme. It measures key indicators that allows countries to generate data for using in policy making and designing programs, and to monitor progress towards the national goals and global commitments.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COLL_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The sample for the Nepal MICS 2019 was designed to provide estimates for a large number of indicators on the situation of children and women at the national level, for urban and rural areas and seven provinces. The urban and rural areas within each province were identified as the main sampling strata. Kathmandu valley urban is included as a separate stratum as it’s characteristics differ from the rest. Each stratum was a separate domain. The sample of household was selected in two stages. Within each stratum, at the first sampling stage a specified number of census enumerations areas (EA), was selected systematically with probability proportional to size. A household listing was carried out within the selected enumeration areas, identifying the households with and without children under 5 years. In total, 25 households with and without children under 5 were selected in each sample enumeration area through systematic random sampling method. To ensure strong representativeness of children under 5 in the sample, household with children under 5 were oversampled. Where 13 households with children under 5 and 12 households without were selected from listing in each enumeration area. A total sample of 512 enumeration area and 12800 households was selected for the survey. As the sample is not self-weighting, sample weights are used for reporting survey results. </p><p>The sampling frame of Nepal is based on the 2011 National population and Housing Census (NPHC). The census frame is a complete list of all census wards created for the 2011 NPHC. At the time of last census, the urban household population constituted 20% of the total household population. According to the latest changes in the administrative structure, following the federalization of the government, the urban household population increased to 65%. CBS updated the population frame to reflect the current status. In designing the sample for the Nepal MICS, it was very useful to review the sample design and results of the MICS conducted in 2014, documented in the Final Report of that survey. </p><p>Therefore, a multi-stage, stratified cluster sampling approach was used for the selection of the survey sample. The primary sampling units (PSUs) selected at the first stage were the enumeration areas (EAs) defined for the census enumeration. A listing of households was conducted in each sample enumeration area, and a sample of households was selected at the second stage.  </p><p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="FREQ_COLL">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REL_CAL_POLICY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>2024</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_SOURCE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPILING_ORG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="INST_MANDATE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>National official statistical agency that is responsible for conducting, survey and census.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="RATIONALE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p> The products made up of entirely of partly from the leaf of tobacco as raw materials, which are intended to be smoked, sucked, chewed, or snuffed and contained highly addictive psychoactive ingredient, nicotine are known as tobacco products. Use of tobacco products lead to chronic disease and death. There is no proven safe level of tobacco use or of second-hand smoke exposure. All daily and non-daily users of tobacco are at risk of a variety of poor health outcomes across the life-course including chronic illness. Reducing the prevalence of current tobacco use will make a large contribution to reducing premature mortality from non-communicable disease.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REC_USE_LIM">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The calculation of this indicator requires to have reliable information on total numbers of daily and non-daily users of tobacco from the age group 15-49 years and total number of men and women age 15-49 years. The quality of such information is heavily dependent on the questionnaire design, the sample size and design and the accuracy of respondents&#39; answers.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_COMP">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Age-standardized prevalence of current tobacco use among persons aged 15 years and older  = Number of daily and non-daily users of tobacco from the age group 15-49 years /Number of men and women age 15-49 years ×100</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DATA_VALIDATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="ADJUSTMENT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="IMPUTATION">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="REG_AGG">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Not applicable</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="DOC_METHOD">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_MGMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics is the official agency to conducts survey and census. It has trained manpower</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSURE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="QUALITY_ASSMNT">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The questionnaires were developed based on the MICS 6 standard questionnaires of UNICEF. It was customized and translated into Nepali, Bhojpuri and Maithili language. After the development of questionnaire, it was pre-tested in Sindhupalchowk and Sindhuli district during March 2019. Based on the results of the pre-test, modifications were made to the wording and translation of the questionnaires. </p><p>Interviewer’s manual in Nepali language was developed which included concepts, definitions, description of each question and fieldwork procedures, etc. to ensure that quality information was collected.</p><p>Team supervisors were responsible for daily monitoring of filed work. It was mandatory to re-interview on one household per cluster. Furthermore, the skills and performance were observed on daily basis.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COVERAGE">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>The data is available by province and rural and urban.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="COMPARABILITY">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>It follows MICS 6 guidelines of UNICEF and can be compared across countries.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
        <gen:ReportedAttribute id="OTHER_DOC">
          
          <com:Text xml:lang="en"><![CDATA[<p>Central Bureau of Statistics (CBS), 2020. Nepal Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey 2019, Survey Findings Report. Kathmandu, Nepal: Central Bureau of Statistics and UNICEF Nepal.</p>]]></com:Text>
          
        </gen:ReportedAttribute>
        
      </gen:AttributeSet>
    </gen:Report>
  </mes:MetadataSet>
  
</mes:GenericMetadata>
        